<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/getting_started/introduction/godot_design_philosophy.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-godot-design-philosophy"></target>
    <section ids="godot-s-design-philosophy doc-godot-design-philosophy" names="godot's\ design\ philosophy doc_godot_design_philosophy">
        <title>Godot's design philosophy</title>
        <paragraph>Now that you've gotten your feet wet, let's talk about Godot's design.</paragraph>
        <paragraph><strong>Every game engine is different and fits different needs.</strong>
            Not only do they offer a range of features, but the design of each engine
            is unique. This leads to different workflows and different ways to form
            your games' structures. This all stems from their respective design philosophies.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>This page is here to help you understand how Godot works, starting
            with some of its core pillars. It is not a list of available features, nor
            is it an engine comparison. To know if any engine can be a good fit for
            your project, you need to try it out for yourself and
            understand its design and limitations.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>Please watch
            <reference name="Godot explained in 7 minutes" refuri="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yS9cuu5o5Ug">Godot explained in 7 minutes</reference><target ids="godot-explained-in-7-minutes" names="godot\ explained\ in\ 7\ minutes" refuri="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yS9cuu5o5Ug"></target>
            if you're looking for an overview of the engine's features.</paragraph>
        <section ids="object-oriented-design-and-composition" names="object-oriented\ design\ and\ composition">
            <title>Object-oriented design and composition</title>
            <paragraph>Godot embraces object-oriented design at its core with its flexible
                scene system and Node hierarchy. It tries to stay away from strict
                programming patterns to offer an intuitive way to structure your game.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>For one, Godot lets you <strong>compose or aggregate</strong> scenes.
                It's like nested prefabs: you can create a BlinkingLight scene and
                a BrokenLantern scene that uses the BlinkingLight.
                Then, create a city filled with BrokenLanterns.
                Change the BlinkingLight's color, save, and all the
                BrokenLanterns in the city will update instantly.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>On top of that, you can <strong>inherit</strong> from any scene.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>A Godot scene could be a Weapon, a Character, an Item, a Door, a Level,
                part of a level… anything you'd like. It works like a class in pure code,
                except you're free to design it by using the editor, using only the
                code, or mixing and matching the two.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>It's different from prefabs you find in several 3D engines, as you can
                then inherit from and extend those scenes. You may create a Magician
                that extends your Character. Modify the Character in the editor and the Magician
                will update as well. It helps you build your projects so that their
                structure matches the game's design.</paragraph>
            <paragraph><image alt="image0" candidates="{'*': 'getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_01.png'}" original_uri="img/engine_design_01.png" uri="getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_01.png"></image></paragraph>
            <paragraph>Also note that Godot offers many different types of objects called
                nodes, each with a specific purpose. Nodes are part of a tree and always
                inherit from their parents up to the Node class. Although the engine
                does feature some nodes like collision shapes that a parent physics
                body will use, most nodes work independently from one another.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>In other words, Godot's nodes do not work like components in some
                other game engines.</paragraph>
            <paragraph><image alt="image1" candidates="{'*': 'getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_02.png'}" original_uri="img/engine_design_02.png" uri="getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_02.png"></image></paragraph>
            <paragraph>Sprite2D is a Node2D, a CanvasItem and a Node. It has all the properties
                and features of its three parent classes, like transforms or the ability
                to draw custom shapes and render with a custom shader.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="all-inclusive-package" names="all-inclusive\ package">
            <title>All-inclusive package</title>
            <paragraph>Godot tries to provide its own tools to answer most common
                needs. It has a dedicated scripting workspace, an animation editor, a
                tilemap editor, a shader editor, a debugger, a profiler,
                the ability to hot-reload locally and on remote devices, etc.</paragraph>
            <paragraph><image alt="image2" candidates="{'*': 'getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_03.png'}" original_uri="img/engine_design_03.png" uri="getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_03.png"></image></paragraph>
            <paragraph>The goal is to offer a full package to create games and a continuous
                user experience. You can still work with external programs as long as
                there is an import plugin available in Godot for it.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>That is also partly why Godot offers its own programming language
                GDScript along with C#. GDScript is designed for the needs
                of game developers and game designers, and is tightly integrated in
                the engine and the editor.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>GDScript lets you write code using an indentation-based syntax,
                yet it detects types and offers a static language's quality of auto-completion.
                It is also optimized for gameplay code with built-in types like Vectors and Colors.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Note that with GDExtension, you can write high-performance code using compiled
                languages like C, C++, Rust, D, Haxe, or Swift without recompiling the engine.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Note that the 3D workspace doesn't feature as many tools as the 2D workspace.
                You'll need external programs or add-ons to edit terrains, animate complex characters, and so on.
                Godot provides a complete API to extend the editor's functionality using
                game code. See <reference name="The Godot editor is a Godot game" refid="the-godot-editor-is-a-godot-game">The Godot editor is a Godot game</reference> below.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="open-source" names="open\ source">
            <title>Open source</title>
            <paragraph>Godot offers a fully open source codebase under the <strong>MIT license</strong>.
                This means that the codebase is free for anyone to download, use,
                modify, or share, as long as its license file is kept intact.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>All technologies that ship with Godot, including third-party libraries, must
                be legally compatible with this open source license. Therefore, most parts
                of Godot are developed from the ground up by community contributors.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Anyone can plug in proprietary tools for the needs of their projects —
                they just won't ship with the engine. This may include Google AdMob,
                or FMOD. Any of these can come as
                third-party plugins instead.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>On the other hand, an open codebase means you can <strong>learn from and extend
                    the engine</strong> to your heart's content. You can also debug games easily,
                as Godot will print errors with a stack trace, even if they come from the engine itself.</paragraph>
            <note>
                <paragraph>This <strong>does not affect the work you do with Godot</strong> in any way: there's
                    no strings attached to the engine or anything you make with it.</paragraph>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section ids="community-driven" names="community-driven">
            <title>Community-driven</title>
            <paragraph><strong>Godot is made by its community, for the community, and for all game
                    creators out there.</strong> It's the needs of the users and open discussions
                that drive the core updates. New features from the core developers often
                focus on what will benefit the most users first.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>That said, although a handful of core developers work on it full-time,
                the project has thousands of contributors at the time of writing. Benevolent
                programmers work on features they may need themselves, so you'll see
                improvements in all corners of the engine at the same time in every
                major release.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="the-godot-editor-is-a-godot-game" names="the\ godot\ editor\ is\ a\ godot\ game">
            <title>The Godot editor is a Godot game</title>
            <paragraph>The Godot editor runs on the game engine. It uses the engine's own UI
                system, it can hot-reload code and scenes when you test your projects,
                or run game code in the editor. This means you can <strong>use the same code</strong>
                and scenes for your games, or <strong>build plugins and extend the editor.</strong></paragraph>
            <paragraph>This leads to a reliable and flexible UI system, as it powers the editor
                itself. With the <literal>@tool</literal> annotation, you can run any game code in the editor.</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id1">
                <image candidates="{'*': 'getting_started/introduction/img/introduction_rpg_in_a_box.webp'}" original_uri="img/introduction_rpg_in_a_box.webp" uri="getting_started/introduction/img/introduction_rpg_in_a_box.webp"></image>
                <caption>RPG in a Box is a voxel RPG editor made with Godot. It uses Godot's
                    UI tools for its node-based programming system and for the rest of the
                    interface.</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>Put the <literal>@tool</literal> annotation at the top of any GDScript file and it will run
                in the editor. This lets you import and export plugins, create plugins
                like custom level editors, or create scripts with the same nodes and API
                you use in your projects.</paragraph>
            <note>
                <paragraph>The editor is fully written in C++ and is statically compiled into the
                    binary. This means you can't import it as a typical project that would have a
                    <literal>project.godot</literal> file.</paragraph>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section ids="separate-2d-and-3d-engines" names="separate\ 2d\ and\ 3d\ engines">
            <title>Separate 2D and 3D engines</title>
            <paragraph>Godot offers dedicated 2D and 3D rendering engines. As a result, <strong>the
                    base unit for 2D scenes is pixels.</strong> Even though the engines are
                separate, you can render 2D in 3D, 3D in 2D, and overlay 2D sprites and
                interfaces over your 3D world.</paragraph>
            <substitution_definition names="image0"><image alt="image0" candidates="{'*': 'getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_01.png'}" original_uri="img/engine_design_01.png" uri="getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_01.png"></image></substitution_definition>
            <substitution_definition names="image1"><image alt="image1" candidates="{'*': 'getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_02.png'}" original_uri="img/engine_design_02.png" uri="getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_02.png"></image></substitution_definition>
            <substitution_definition names="image2"><image alt="image2" candidates="{'*': 'getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_03.png'}" original_uri="img/engine_design_03.png" uri="getting_started/introduction/img/engine_design_03.png"></image></substitution_definition>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
