<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/3d/particles/process_material_properties.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-process-material-properties"></target>
    <section ids="process-material-properties doc-process-material-properties" names="process\ material\ properties doc_process_material_properties">
        <title>Process material properties</title>
        <figure align="right" ids="id1">
            <image alt="ParticleProcessMaterial properties" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_minmaxcurve.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_minmaxcurve.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_minmaxcurve.webp"></image>
            <caption>Min, max, and curve properties</caption>
        </figure>
        <paragraph>The properties in this material control how particles behave and change over their lifetime.
            A lot of them have <literal>Min</literal>, <literal>Max</literal>, and <literal>Curve</literal> values that allow you to fine-tune
            their behavior. The relationship between these values is this: When a particle is spawned,
            the property is set with a random value between <literal>Min</literal> and <literal>Max</literal>. If <literal>Min</literal> and <literal>Max</literal> are
            the same, the value will always be the same for every particle. If the <literal>Curve</literal> is also set,
            the value of the property will be multiplied by the value of the curve at the current point
            in a particle's lifetime. Use the curve to change a property over the particle lifetime. Very
            complex behavior can be expressed this way.</paragraph>
        <note>
            <paragraph>This page covers how to use ParticleProcessMaterial for 3D scenes specifically.
                For information on how to use it in a 2D Scene see <reference internal="True" refuri="../../2d/particle_process_material_2d#doc-particle-process-material-2d"><inline classes="std std-ref">ParticleProcessMaterial 2D Usage</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
        </note>
        <section ids="time" names="time">
            <title>Time</title>
            <paragraph>The <literal>Lifetime Randomness</literal> property controls how much randomness to apply to each particle's
                lifetime. A value of <literal>0</literal> means there is no randomness at all and all particles live for
                the same amount of time, set by the <reference internal="True" refuri="properties#doc-3d-particles-properties-time"><inline classes="std std-ref">Lifetime</inline></reference> property. A value of <literal>1</literal> means
                that a particle's lifetime is completely random within the range of [0.0, <literal>Lifetime</literal>].</paragraph>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section ids="particle-flags" names="particle\ flags">
        <title>Particle flags</title>
        <paragraph>The <literal>Align Y</literal> property aligns each particle's Y-axis with its velocity. Enabling this
            property is the same as setting the <reference internal="True" refuri="properties#doc-3d-particles-properties-draw"><inline classes="std std-ref">Transform Align</inline></reference> property to
            <literal>Y to Velocity</literal>.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>The <literal>Rotate Y</literal> property works with the properties in the <reference name="Angle" refuri="#angle">Angle</reference> and
            <reference name="Angular Velocity" refuri="#angular-velocity">Angular Velocity</reference> groups to control particle rotation. <literal>Rotate Y</literal>
            has to be enabled if you want to apply any rotation to particles. The exception to this
            is any particle that uses the <reference internal="True" refuri="../standard_material_3d#doc-standard-material-3d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Standard Material</inline></reference>
            where the <literal>Billboard</literal> property is set to <literal>Particle Billboard</literal>. In that case, particles
            rotate even without <literal>Rotate Y</literal> enabled.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>When the <literal>Disable Z</literal> property is enabled, particles will not move along the Z-axis.
            Whether that is going to be the particle system's local Z-axis or the world Z-axis is
            determined by the <reference internal="True" refuri="properties#doc-3d-particles-properties-draw"><inline classes="std std-ref">Local Coords</inline></reference> property.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>The <literal>Damping as Friction</literal> property changes the behavior of damping from a constant
            deceleration to a deceleration based on speed.</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section ids="spawn" names="spawn">
        <title>Spawn</title>
        <target refid="doc-process-material-properties-shapes"></target>
        <section ids="emission-shape doc-process-material-properties-shapes" names="emission\ shape doc_process_material_properties_shapes">
            <title>Emission shape</title>
            <paragraph>Particles can emit from a single point in space or in a way that they fill out a shape.
                The <literal>Shape</literal> property controls that shape. <literal>Point</literal> is the default value. All
                particles emit from a single point in the center of the particle system. When set to <literal>Sphere</literal>
                or <literal>Box</literal>, particles emit in a way that they fill out a sphere or a box shape evenly.
                You have full control over the size of these shapes. <literal>Sphere Surface</literal> works like <literal>Sphere</literal>,
                but instead of filling it out, all particles spawn on the sphere's surface.</paragraph>
            <figure ids="id2">
                <image alt="Simple particle emission shapes" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_shapes_simple.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_shapes_simple.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_shapes_simple.webp"></image>
                <caption>Particles emitting from a point (left), in a sphere (middle), and in a box (right)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure align="right" ids="id3">
                <image alt="Ring-shaped particle system" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_ring.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_ring.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_ring.webp"></image>
                <caption>A ring-shaped particle system</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>The <literal>Ring</literal> emission shape makes particles emit in the shape of a ring. You can control the ring's
                direction by changing the <literal>Ring Axis</literal> property. <literal>Ring Height</literal> controls the thickness
                of the ring along its axis. <literal>Ring Radius</literal> and <literal>Ring Inner Radius</literal> control how wide
                the ring is and how large the hole in the middle should be. The image shows a particle
                system with a radius of <literal>2</literal> and an inner radius of <literal>1.5</literal>, the axis points along the
                global Z-axis.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>In addition to these relatively simple shapes, you can select the <literal>Points</literal> or
                <literal>Directed Points</literal> option to create highly complex emission shapes. See the
                <reference internal="True" refuri="complex_shapes#doc-3d-particles-complex-shapes"><inline classes="std std-ref">Complex emission shapes</inline></reference> section for a detailed
                explanation of how to set these up.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="angle" names="angle">
            <title>Angle</title>
            <paragraph>The <literal>Angle</literal> property controls a particle's starting rotation <reference name="as described above" refuri="#process-material-properties">as described above</reference>.
                In order to have an actual effect on the particle, you have to enable one of two properties: <reference name="Rotate Y" refuri="#particle-flags">Rotate Y</reference>
                rotates the particle around the particle system's Y-axis. The <literal>Billboard</literal> property in
                the <reference internal="True" refuri="../standard_material_3d#doc-standard-material-3d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Standard Material</inline></reference>, if it is set to <literal>Particle Billboard</literal>, rotates
                the particle around the axis that points from the particle to the camera.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="direction" names="direction">
            <title>Direction</title>
            <note>
                <paragraph>The <literal>Direction</literal> property alone is not enough to see any particle movement. Whatever
                    values you set here only take effect once velocity or acceleration properties are set, too.</paragraph>
            </note>
            <paragraph>The <literal>Direction</literal> property is a vector that controls each particle's direction of movement
                at the moment it is spawned. A value of <literal>(X=1,Y=0,Z=0)</literal> would make all particles move
                sideways along the X-axis. For something like a fountain where particles shoot out up in the
                air, a value of <literal>(X=0,Y=1,Z=0)</literal> would be a good starting point.</paragraph>
            <figure ids="id4">
                <image alt="Different values for particle direction" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_direction.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_direction.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_direction.webp"></image>
                <caption>Different direction values: Y-axis only (left), equal values for X and Y (middle), X and Y with gravity enabled (right)</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>After setting a direction, you will notice that all particles move in the same direction in
                a straight line. The <literal>Spread</literal> property adds some variation and randomness to each particle's
                direction. The higher the value, the stronger the deviation from the original path. A value
                of <literal>0</literal> means there is no spread at all while a value of <literal>180</literal> makes particles shoot out in
                every direction. You could use this for something like pieces of debris during an explosion effect.</paragraph>
            <figure ids="id5">
                <image alt="Different values for particle spread" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_spread.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_spread.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_spread.webp"></image>
                <caption>No spread (left), 45 degree angle (middle), full 180 degrees (right)</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>The <literal>Flatness</literal> property limits the spread along the Y-axis. A value of <literal>0</literal> means there
                is no limit and a value of <literal>1</literal> will eliminate all particle movement along the Y-axis. The
                particles will spread out completely "flat".</paragraph>
            <paragraph>You won't see any actual movement until you also set some values for the velocity and
                acceleration properties below, so let's take a look at those next.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="initial-velocity" names="initial\ velocity">
            <title>Initial velocity</title>
            <paragraph>While the <literal>Direction</literal> property controls a particle's movement direction, the <literal>Initial Velocity</literal>
                controls how fast it goes. It's separated into <literal>Velocity Min</literal> and <literal>Velocity Max</literal>, both
                set to <literal>0</literal> by default, which is why you don't see any movement initially. As soon as you set
                values for either of these properties <reference name="as described above" refuri="#process-material-properties">as described above</reference>, the
                particles begin to move. The direction is multiplied by these values, so you can make particles
                move in the opposite direction by setting a negative velocity.</paragraph>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section ids="accelerations" names="accelerations">
        <title>Accelerations</title>
        <section ids="gravity" names="gravity">
            <title>Gravity</title>
            <paragraph>The next few property groups work closely together to control particle movement and rotation.
                <literal>Gravity</literal> drags particles in the direction it points at, which is straight down at the strength
                of Earth's gravity by default. Gravity affects all particle movement.
                If your game uses physics and the world's gravity can change at runtime, you can use this property
                to keep the game's gravity in sync with particle gravity. A <literal>Gravity</literal> value of <literal>(X=0,Y=0,Z=0)</literal> means
                no particle will ever move at all if none of the other movement properties are set.</paragraph>
            <figure ids="id6">
                <image alt="Different values for particle gravity" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_gravity.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_gravity.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_gravity.webp"></image>
                <caption>Left: (X=0,Y=-9.8,Z=0), middle: (X=0,Y=9.8,Z=0), right: (X=4,Y=2,Z=0).</caption>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section ids="angular-velocity" names="angular\ velocity">
            <title>Angular velocity</title>
            <paragraph><literal>Angular Velocity</literal> controls a particle's speed of rotation <reference name="as described above" refuri="#process-material-properties">as described above</reference>.
                You can reverse the direction by using negative numbers for <literal>Velocity Min</literal> or <literal>Velocity Max</literal>. Like the
                <reference name="Angle" refuri="#angle">Angle</reference> property, the rotation will only be visible if the <reference name="Rotate Y" refuri="#particle-flags">Rotate Y</reference> flag is set
                or the <literal>Particle Billboard</literal> mode is selected in the <reference internal="True" refuri="../standard_material_3d#doc-standard-material-3d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Standard Material</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
            <note>
                <paragraph>The <reference name="Damping" refuri="#damping">Damping</reference> property has no effect on the angular velocity.</paragraph>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section ids="linear-acceleration" names="linear\ acceleration">
            <title>Linear acceleration</title>
            <paragraph>A particle's velocity is a constant value: once it's set, it doesn't change and the particle will
                always move at the same speed. You can use the <literal>Linear Accel</literal> property to
                change the speed of movement over a particle's lifetime <reference name="as described above" refuri="#process-material-properties">as described above</reference>.
                Positive values will speed up the particle and make it move faster. Negative values will slow it
                down until it stops and starts moving in the other direction.</paragraph>
            <figure ids="id7">
                <image alt="Different values for particle linear acceleration" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_accel_linear.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_accel_linear.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_accel_linear.webp"></image>
                <caption>Negative (top) and positive (bottom) linear acceleration</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>It's important to keep in mind that when we change acceleration, we're not changing the velocity
                directly, we're changing the <emphasis>change</emphasis> in velocity. A value of <literal>0</literal> on the acceleration curve
                does not stop the particle's movement, it stops the change in the particle's movement. Whatever
                its velocity was at that moment, it will keep moving at that velocity until the acceleration is
                changed again.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="radial-acceleration" names="radial\ acceleration">
            <title>Radial acceleration</title>
            <paragraph>The <literal>Radial Accel</literal> property adds a gravity-like force to all particles, with the origin
                of that force at the particle system's current location. Negative values make particles move
                towards the center, like the force of gravity from a planet on objects in its orbit. Positive
                values make particles move away from the center.</paragraph>
            <figure ids="id8">
                <image alt="Different values for particle radial acceleration" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_accel_radial.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_accel_radial.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_accel_radial.webp"></image>
                <caption>Negative (left) and positive (right) radial acceleration</caption>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section ids="tangential-acceleration" names="tangential\ acceleration">
            <title>Tangential acceleration</title>
            <figure align="right" ids="id9">
                <image alt="Tangents on a circle" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_tangent.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_tangent.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_tangent.webp"></image>
                <caption>Tangents on a circle</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>This property adds particle acceleration in the direction of the tangent to a circle on the particle
                system's XZ-plane with the origin at the system's center and a radius the distance between each
                particle's current location and the system's center projected onto that plane.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Let's unpack that.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>A tangent to a circle is a straight line that "touches" the circle in a right angle to the circle's
                radius at the touch point. A circle on the particle system's XZ-plane is the circle that you see
                when you look straight down at the particle system from above.</paragraph>
            <figure align="right" ids="id10">
                <image alt="Tangential acceleration from above" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_accel_tangent.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_accel_tangent.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_accel_tangent.webp"></image>
                <caption>Tangential acceleration from above</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph><literal>Tangential Accel</literal> is always limited to that plane and never move particles along the system's Y-axis.
                A particle's location is enough to define such a circle where the distance to the system's center is
                the radius if we ignore the vector's Y component.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The <literal>Tangential Accel</literal> property will make particles orbit the particle system's center, but the
                radius will increase constantly. Viewed from above, particles will move away from the center
                in a spiral. Negative values reverse the direction.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="damping" names="damping">
            <title>Damping</title>
            <paragraph>The <literal>Damping</literal> property gradually stops all movement. Each frame, a particle's movement
                is slowed down a little unless the total acceleration is greater than the damping effect. If
                it isn't, the particle will keep slowing down until it doesn't move at all. The greater the value, the less
                time it takes to bring particles to a complete halt.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="attractor-interaction" names="attractor\ interaction">
            <title>Attractor interaction</title>
            <paragraph>If you want the particle system to interact with <reference internal="True" refuri="attractors#doc-3d-particles-attractors"><inline classes="std std-ref">particle attractors</inline></reference>,
                you have to check the <literal>Enabled</literal> property. When it is disabled, the particle system
                ignores all particle attractors.</paragraph>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section ids="display" names="display">
        <title>Display</title>
        <section ids="scale" names="scale">
            <title>Scale</title>
            <paragraph><literal>Scale</literal> controls a particle's size <reference name="as described above" refuri="#process-material-properties">as described above</reference>. You can set
                different values for <literal>Scale Min</literal> and <literal>Scale Max</literal> to randomize each particle's size. Negative values
                are not allowed, so you won't be able to flip particles with this property. If you emit particles as
                billboards, the <literal>Keep Size</literal> property on the <reference internal="True" refuri="../standard_material_3d#doc-standard-material-3d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Standard Material</inline></reference>
                in your draw passes has to be enabled for any scaling to have an effect.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="color" names="color">
            <title>Color</title>
            <paragraph>The <literal>Color</literal> property controls a particle's initial color. It will have an effect only after the
                <literal>Use As Albedo</literal> property in the <literal>Vertex Color</literal> group of the <reference internal="True" refuri="../standard_material_3d#doc-standard-material-3d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Standard Material</inline></reference>
                is enabled. This property is multiplied with color coming from the particle material's
                own <literal>Color</literal> or <literal>Texture</literal> property.</paragraph>
            <figure align="right" ids="id11">
                <image alt="Particle color ramp" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_ramp.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_ramp.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_ramp.webp"></image>
                <caption>Setting up a color ramp</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>There are two <literal>Ramp</literal> properties in the <literal>Color</literal> group. These allow you to define a range of colors
                that are used to set the particle's color. The <literal>Color Ramp</literal> property changes a particle's color
                over the course of its lifetime. It moves through the entire range of colors you defined.
                The <literal>Color Initial Ramp</literal> property selects the particle's initial color from a random
                position on the color ramp.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>To set up a color ramp, click on the box next to the property name and from the dropdown menu
                select <literal>New GradientTexture1D</literal>. Click on the box again to open the texture's details.
                Find the <literal>Gradient</literal> property, click on the box next to it and select <literal>New Gradient</literal>.
                Click on that box again and you will see a color range. Click anywhere on that range
                to insert a new marker. You can move the marker with the mouse and delete it by clicking
                the right mouse button. When a marker is selected, you can use the color picker next to
                the range to change its color.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="hue-variation" names="hue\ variation">
            <title>Hue variation</title>
            <paragraph>Like the <literal>Color</literal> property, <literal>Hue Variation</literal> controls a particle's color, but in a
                different way. It does so not by setting color values directly, but by
                <emphasis>shifting the color's hue</emphasis>.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Hue describes a color's pigment: red, orange, yellow, green and so on. It does not
                tell you anything about how bright or how saturated the color is. The <literal>Hue Variation</literal>
                property controls the range of available hues <reference name="as described above" refuri="#process-material-properties">as described above</reference>.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>It works on top of the particle's current color. The values you set for
                <literal>Variation Min</literal> and <literal>Variation Max</literal> control how far the hue is allowed to shift
                in either direction. A higher value leads to more color variation while a low value
                limits the available colors to the closest neighbors of the original color.</paragraph>
            <figure ids="id12">
                <image alt="Different values for hue variation" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_hue.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_hue.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_hue.webp"></image>
                <caption>Different values for hue variation, both times with blue as base color: 0.6 (left) and 0.1 (right)</caption>
            </figure>
            <target refid="doc-process-material-properties-animation"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="animation doc-process-material-properties-animation" names="animation doc_process_material_properties_animation">
            <title>Animation</title>
            <paragraph>The <literal>Animation</literal> property group controls the behavior of sprite
                sheet animations in the particle's <reference internal="True" refuri="../standard_material_3d#doc-standard-material-3d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Standard Material</inline></reference>.
                The <literal>Min</literal>, <literal>Max</literal>, and <literal>Curve</literal> values work <reference name="as described above" refuri="#process-material-properties">as described above</reference>.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>An animated sprite sheet is a texture that contains several smaller images aligned on a grid.
                The images are shown one after the other so fast that they combine to play a short
                animation, like a flipbook. You can use them for animated particles like smoke or fire.
                These are the steps to create an animated particle system:</paragraph>
            <figure align="right" ids="id13">
                <image alt="A sprite sheet" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_sprite.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_sprite.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_sprite.webp"></image>
                <caption>An 8x8 animated smoke sprite sheet</caption>
            </figure>
            <enumerated_list enumtype="arabic" prefix="" suffix=".">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Import a sprite sheet texture into the engine. If you don't have one at hand, you can download the <download_reference filename="0e9010cdc7bfae0d0bed55a967d66e0b/particle_sprite_smoke.webp" refdoc="tutorials/3d/particles/process_material_properties" refdomain="" refexplicit="True" reftarget="img/particle_sprite_smoke.webp" reftype="download" refwarn="False"><literal classes="xref download">high-res version of the example image</literal></download_reference>.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Set up a particle system with at least one draw pass and assign a <literal>Standard Material</literal> to the mesh in that draw pass.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Assign the sprite sheet to the <literal>Texture</literal> property in the <literal>Albedo</literal> group</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Set the material's <literal>Billboard</literal> property to <literal>Particle Billboard</literal>. Doing so makes the <literal>Particles Anim</literal> group available in the material.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Set <literal>H Frames</literal> to the number of columns and <literal>V Frames</literal> to the number of rows in the sprite sheet.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Check <literal>Loop</literal> if you want the animation to keep repeating.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </enumerated_list>
            <paragraph>That's it for the Standard Material. You won't see any animation right away. This is
                where the <literal>Animation</literal> properties come in. The <literal>Speed</literal> properties control how fast
                the sprite sheet animates. Set <literal>Speed Min</literal> and <literal>Speed Max</literal> to <literal>1</literal> and you should see the
                animation playing. The <literal>Offset</literal> properties control where the animation starts on a
                newly spawned particle. By default, it will always be the first image in the sequence.
                You can add some variety by changing <literal>Offset Min</literal> and <literal>Offset Max</literal> to randomize
                the starting position.</paragraph>
            <figure ids="id14">
                <image alt="Animated particles" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_animate.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_animate.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_animate.webp"></image>
                <caption>Three different particle systems using the same smoke sprite sheet</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>Depending on how many images your sprite sheet contains and for how long your
                particle is alive, the animation might not look smooth. The relationship between
                particle lifetime, animation speed, and number of images in the sprite sheet is
                this:</paragraph>
            <note>
                <paragraph>At an animation speed of <literal>1.0</literal>, the animation will reach the last image
                    in the sequence just as the particle's lifetime ends.</paragraph>
                <math_block docname="tutorials/3d/particles/process_material_properties" label="True" nowrap="False" number="True" xml:space="preserve">Animation\ FPS = \frac{Number\ of\ images}{Lifetime}

</math_block>
            </note>
            <paragraph>If your sprite sheet contains
                64 (8x8) images and the particle's lifetime is set to <literal>1 second</literal>, the animation
                will be very smooth at <strong>64 FPS</strong> (1 second / 64 images). if the lifetime is set to <literal>2 seconds</literal>, it
                will still be fairly smooth at <strong>32 FPS</strong>. But if the particle is alive for
                <literal>8 seconds</literal>, the animation will be visibly choppy at <strong>8 FPS</strong>. In order to make the
                animation smooth again, you need to increase the animation speed to something like <literal>3</literal>
                to reach an acceptable framerate.</paragraph>
            <figure ids="id15">
                <image alt="Animated particles lifetimes" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_animate_lifetime.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_animate_lifetime.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_animate_lifetime.webp"></image>
                <caption>The same particle system at different lifetimes: 1 second (left), 2 seconds (middle), 8 seconds (right)</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>Note that the GPUParticles3D node's <strong>Fixed FPS</strong> also affects animation
                playback. For smooth animation playback, it's recommended to set it to 0 so that
                the particle is simulated on every rendered frame. If this is not an option for
                your use case, set <strong>Fixed FPS</strong> to be equal to the effective framerate used by
                the flipbook animation (see above for the formula).</paragraph>
            <target refid="doc-process-material-properties-turbulence"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="turbulence doc-process-material-properties-turbulence" names="turbulence doc_process_material_properties_turbulence">
            <title>Turbulence</title>
            <paragraph>Turbulence adds noise to particle movement, creating interesting and lively patterns.
                Check the box next to the <literal>Enabled</literal> property to activate it. A number
                of new properties show up that control the movement speed, noise pattern and overall influence
                on the particle system. You can find a detailed explanation of these in the section on
                <reference internal="True" refuri="turbulence#doc-3d-particles-turbulence"><inline classes="std std-ref">particle turbulence</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
            <target refid="doc-process-material-properties-subemitter"></target>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section ids="collision doc-process-material-properties-subemitter" names="collision doc_process_material_properties_subemitter">
        <title>Collision</title>
        <paragraph>The <literal>Mode</literal> property controls how and if emitters collide with particle collision nodes. Set it
            to <literal>Disabled</literal> to disable any collision for this particle system. Set it to <literal>Hide On Contact</literal>
            if you want particles to disappear as soon as they collide. Set it to <literal>Constant</literal> to make
            particles collide and bounce around. You will see two new properties appear in the inspector.
            They control how particles behave during collision events.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>A high <literal>Friction</literal> value will reduce sliding along surfaces. This is especially
            helpful if particles collide with sloped surfaces and you want them to stay in
            place instead of sliding all the way to the bottom, like snow falling on a mountain.
            A high <literal>Bounce</literal> value will make particles bounce off surfaces they collide with,
            like rubber balls on a solid floor.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>If the <literal>Use Scale</literal> property is enabled, the <reference internal="True" refuri="properties#doc-3d-particles-properties-collision"><inline classes="std std-ref">collision base size</inline></reference>
            is multiplied by the particle's <reference name="current scale" refuri="#scale">current scale</reference>. You can use this to
            make sure that the rendered size and the collision size match for particles
            with random scale or scale that varies over time.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>You can learn more about particle collisions in the <reference internal="True" refuri="collision#doc-3d-particles-collision"><inline classes="std std-ref">Collisions</inline></reference>
            section in this manual.</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section ids="sub-emitter" names="sub-emitter">
        <title>Sub-emitter</title>
        <figure align="right" ids="id16">
            <image alt="Sub-emitter modes" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_sub_mode.webp'}" original_uri="img/particle_sub_mode.webp" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_sub_mode.webp"></image>
            <caption>The available sub-emitter modes</caption>
        </figure>
        <paragraph>The <literal>Mode</literal> property controls how and when sub-emitters are spawned. Set it to <literal>Disabled</literal>
            and no sub-emitters will ever be spawned. Set it to <literal>Constant</literal> to make sub-emitters
            spawn continuously at a constant rate. The <literal>Frequency</literal> property controls how often
            that happens within the span of one second. Set the mode to <literal>At End</literal> to make the sub-emitter
            spawn at the end of the parent particle's lifetime, right before it is destroyed. The
            <literal>Amount At End</literal> property controls how many sub-emitters will be spawned. Set the
            mode to <literal>At Collision</literal> to make sub-emitters spawn when a particle collides with the
            environment. The <literal>Amount At Collision</literal> property controls how many sub-emitters will be spawned.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>When the <literal>Keep Velocity</literal> property is enabled, the newly spawned sub-emitter starts off
            with the parent particle's velocity at the time the sub-emitter is created.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>See the <reference internal="True" refuri="subemitters#doc-3d-particles-subemitters"><inline classes="std std-ref">Sub-emitters</inline></reference> section in this manual for a detailed explanation of how
            to add a sub-emitter to a particle system.</paragraph>
        <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
    </section>
</document>
