<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.17.1 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/3d/particles/subemitters.rst" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-3d-particles-subemitters"></target>
    <section ids="particle-sub-emitters doc-3d-particles-subemitters" names="particle\ sub-emitters doc_3d_particles_subemitters">
        <title>Particle sub-emitters</title>
        <figure>
            <image alt="Chained sub-emitters" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_sub_chain.webp'}" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_sub_chain.webp"></image>
        </figure>
        <paragraph>Sometimes a visual effect cannot be created with a single particle system alone.
            Sometimes a particle system needs to be spawned as a response to something that happens in
            another particle system. Fireworks are a good example of that. They usually consist of
            several stages of explosions that happen in sequence. Sub-emitters are a good way to achieve
            this kind of effect.</paragraph>
        <figure align="right" ids="id1">
            <image alt="指定子发射器" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_sub_assign.webp'}" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_sub_assign.webp"></image>
            <caption>Click to assign a sub-emitter...</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure align="right" ids="id2">
            <image alt="List particle systems" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_sub_list.webp'}" uri="tutorials/3d/particles/img/particle_sub_list.webp"></image>
            <caption>...and select one from the scene</caption>
        </figure>
        <paragraph>A sub-emitter is a particle system that spawns as a child of another particle system.
            You can add sub-emitters to sub-emitters, chaining particle effects as deep as you like.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>To create a sub-emitter, you need at least two particle systems in the same scene. One of them will be the
            parent and one will be set as the child. Find the <literal>Sub Emitter</literal> property on the parent
            and click the box next to it to assign the sub-emitter. You will see a list of available particle
            systems in the scene. Select one and click the confirmation button.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>Particle systems from instanced scenes can be set as sub-emitters too, as long as the
            <literal>Editable Children</literal> property is enabled on the instanced scene. This also works the other
            way around: You can assign a sub-emitter to a particle system in an instanced scene,
            even one coming from a different instanced scene.</paragraph>
        <note>
            <paragraph>When you set a particle system as the sub-emitter of another, the system stops
                emitting, even if the <literal>Emitting</literal> property was checked. Don't worry, it didn't break. This happens
                to every particle system as soon as it becomes a sub-emitter. You also won't be able to
                re-enable the property as long as the particle system is used as a sub-emitter.</paragraph>
        </note>
        <warning>
            <paragraph>Even though the parent particle system can be selected from the list of available particle
                systems, a particle system which is its own sub-emitter does not work in Godot. It will
                simply not spawn. The same is true for any other kind of recursive or self-referential
                sub-emitter setup.</paragraph>
        </warning>
        <section ids="emitter-mode" names="emitter\ mode">
            <title>Emitter mode</title>
            <paragraph>When you assign a sub-emitter, you don't see it spawn right away. Emitting is disabled
                by default and needs to be enabled first. Set the <literal>Mode</literal> property in the <literal>Sub Emitter</literal> group
                of the <reference internal="True" refuri="process_material_properties#doc-process-material-properties-subemitter"><inline classes="std std-ref">ParticleProcessMaterial</inline></reference> to something other than <literal>Disabled</literal>.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The emitter mode also determines how many sub-emitter particles are spawned. <literal>Constant</literal>
                spawns a single particle at a frequency set by the <literal>Frequency</literal> property. For <literal>At End</literal>
                and <literal>At Collision</literal> you can set the amount directly with the <literal>Amount At End</literal> and the
                <literal>Amount At Collision</literal> properties.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="limitations" names="limitations 限制">
            <title>限制</title>
            <paragraph>One thing to keep in mind is that the total number of active particles from the sub-emitter
                is always capped by the <literal>Amount</literal> property on the sub-emitter particle system. If you find
                that there are not enough particles spawned from the sub-emitter, you might have to increase
                the amount in the particle system.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Some emitter properties are ignored when a particle system is spawned as a sub-emitter.
                The <literal>Explosiveness</literal> property, for example, has no effect. Depending on the emitter mode,
                the particles are either spawned sequentially at fixed intervals or explosively all at once.</paragraph>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/zh_CN/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="翻译状态" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/zh_CN/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/zh_CN/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
