<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/audio/audio_effects.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-audio-effects"></target>
    <section ids="audio-effects doc-audio-effects" names="audio\ effects doc_audio_effects">
        <title>Audio effects</title>
        <paragraph>Godot includes several audio effects that can be added to an audio bus to
            alter every sound file that goes through that bus.</paragraph>
        <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses4.webp'}" original_uri="img/audio_buses4.webp" uri="tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses4.webp"></image>
        <paragraph>Try them all out to get a sense of how they alter sound. Here follows a short
            description of the available effects:</paragraph>
        <section ids="amplify" names="amplify">
            <title>Amplify</title>
            <paragraph>Amplify changes the volume of the signal. Some care needs to be taken, though:
                setting the level too high can make the sound digitally clip, which can produce
                unpleasant crackles and pops.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="bandlimit-and-bandpass" names="bandlimit\ and\ bandpass">
            <title>BandLimit and BandPass</title>
            <paragraph>These are resonant filters which block frequencies around the <emphasis>Cutoff</emphasis> point.
                BandPass can be used to simulate sound passing through an old telephone line or
                megaphone. Modulating the BandPass frequency can simulate the sound of a wah-wah
                guitar pedal, think of the guitar in Jimi Hendrix's <emphasis>Voodoo Child (Slight
                    Return)</emphasis>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="capture" names="capture">
            <title>Capture</title>
            <paragraph>The Capture effect copies the audio frames of the audio bus that it is on into
                an internal buffer. This can be used to capture data from the microphone
                or to transmit audio over the network in real-time.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="chorus" names="chorus">
            <title>Chorus</title>
            <paragraph>As the name of the effect implies, the Chorus effect makes a single audio sample
                sound like an entire chorus. It does this by duplicating a signal and very
                slightly altering the timing and pitch of each duplicate, and varying that
                over time via an LFO (low frequency oscillator). The duplicate(s) are then
                mixed back together with the original signal, producing a lush, wide, and
                large sound. Although chorus is traditionally used for voices, it can be
                desirable with almost any type of sound.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="compressor" names="compressor">
            <title>Compressor</title>
            <paragraph>A dynamic range compressor automatically attenuates (ducks) the level of the incoming
                signal when its amplitude exceeds a certain threshold. The level of attenuation
                applied is proportional to how far the incoming audio exceeds the threshold.
                The compressor's Ratio parameter controls the degree of attenuation.
                One of the main uses of a compressor is to reduce the dynamic range of signals
                with very loud and quiet parts. Reducing the dynamic range of a signal
                can make it fit more comfortably in a mix.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The compressor has many uses. For example:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>It can be used in the Master bus to compress the whole output prior to being hit by a limiter, making the effect of the limiter much more subtle.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>It can be used in voice channels to ensure they sound as even as possible.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>It can be <emphasis>sidechained</emphasis> by another sound source. This means it can reduce the sound level
                        of one signal using the level of another audio bus for threshold detection.
                        This technique is very common in video game mixing to "duck" the level of
                        music or sound effects when in-game or multiplayer voices need to be fully audible.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>It can accentuate transients by using a slower attack.
                        This can make sound effects more punchy.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <note>
                <paragraph>If your goal is to prevent a signal from exceeding a given amplitude
                    altogether, rather than to reduce the dynamic range of the signal,
                    a <reference internal="True" refid="doc-audio-buses-limiter"><inline classes="std std-ref">limiter</inline></reference> is likely a better choice
                    than a compressor for this purpose. However, applying compression before
                    a limiter is still good practice.</paragraph>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section ids="delay" names="delay">
            <title>Delay</title>
            <paragraph>Digital delay essentially duplicates a signal and repeats it at a specified
                speed with a volume level that decays for each repeat. Delay is great for
                simulating the acoustic space of a canyon or large room, where sound bounces
                have a lot of <emphasis>delay</emphasis> between their repeats. This is in contrast to reverb,
                which has a more natural and blurred sound to it. Using this in conjunction
                with reverb can create very natural sounding environments!</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="distortion" names="distortion">
            <title>Distortion</title>
            <paragraph>Makes the sound distorted. Godot offers several types of distortion:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><emphasis>Overdrive</emphasis> sounds like a guitar distortion pedal or megaphone. Sounds distorted with this sound like they're coming through
                        a low-quality speaker or device.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><emphasis>Tan</emphasis> sounds like another interesting flavor of overdrive.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><emphasis>Bit crushing</emphasis> clamps the amplitude of the signal, making it sound flat and crunchy.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>All three types of distortion can add higher frequency sounds to an original sound, making it stand out better in a mix.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="eq" names="eq">
            <title>EQ</title>
            <paragraph>EQ is what all other equalizers inherit from. It can be extended with Custom
                scripts to create an equalizer with a custom number of bands.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="eq6-eq10-eq21" names="eq6,\ eq10,\ eq21">
            <title>EQ6, EQ10, EQ21</title>
            <paragraph>Godot provides three equalizers with different numbers of bands, which
                are represented in the title (6, 10, and 21 bands, respectively).
                An equalizer on the Master bus can be useful for cutting low and high
                frequencies that the device's speakers can't reproduce well.
                For example, phone or tablet speakers usually don't reproduce
                low frequency sounds well, and could make a limiter or compressor
                attenuate sounds that aren't even audible to the user anyway.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Note: The equalizer effect can be disabled when headphones are plugged in, giving the user the best of both worlds.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="filter" names="filter">
            <title>Filter</title>
            <paragraph>Filter is what all other filters inherit from and should not be used directly.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="hardlimiter" names="hardlimiter">
            <title>HardLimiter</title>
            <paragraph>A limiter is similar to a compressor, but it's less flexible and designed to
                prevent a signal's amplitude exceeding a given dB threshold. Adding a limiter to the final point of
                the Master bus is good practice, as it offers an easy safeguard against clipping.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="highpassfilter" names="highpassfilter">
            <title>HighPassFilter</title>
            <paragraph>Cuts frequencies below a specific <emphasis>Cutoff</emphasis> frequency.
                HighPassFilter is used to reduce the bass content of a
                signal.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="highshelffilter" names="highshelffilter">
            <title>HighShelfFilter</title>
            <paragraph>Reduces all frequencies above a specific <emphasis>Cutoff</emphasis> frequency.</paragraph>
            <target refid="doc-audio-buses-limiter"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="limiter doc-audio-buses-limiter" names="limiter doc_audio_buses_limiter">
            <title>Limiter</title>
            <paragraph>This is the old limiter effect, and it is recommended to use the new HardLimiter
                effect instead.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Here is an example of how this effect works, if the ceiling is set to -12 dB, and the
                threshold is 0 dB, all samples going through get reduced by 12dB. This changes the
                waveform of the sound and introduces distortion.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>This effect is being kept to preserve compatibility, however it should be considered
                deprecated.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="lowpassfilter" names="lowpassfilter">
            <title>LowPassFilter</title>
            <paragraph>Cuts frequencies above a specific <emphasis>Cutoff</emphasis> frequency and can also resonate
                (boost frequencies close to the <emphasis>Cutoff</emphasis> frequency). Low pass filters can be
                used to simulate "muffled" sound. For instance, underwater sounds, sounds
                blocked by walls, or distant sounds.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="lowshelffilter" names="lowshelffilter">
            <title>LowShelfFilter</title>
            <paragraph>Reduces all frequencies below a specific <emphasis>Cutoff</emphasis> frequency.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="notchfilter" names="notchfilter">
            <title>NotchFilter</title>
            <paragraph>The opposite of the BandPassFilter, it removes a band of sound from the
                frequency spectrum at a given <emphasis>Cutoff</emphasis> frequency.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="panner" names="panner">
            <title>Panner</title>
            <paragraph>The Panner allows the stereo balance of a signal to be adjusted between
                the left and right channels. Headphones are recommended when configuring in this effect.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="phaser" names="phaser">
            <title>Phaser</title>
            <paragraph>This effect is formed by de-phasing two duplicates of the same sound so
                they cancel each other out in an interesting way. Phaser produces a
                pleasant whooshing sound that moves back and forth through the audio
                spectrum, and can be a great way to create sci-fi effects or Darth
                Vader-like voices.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="pitchshift" names="pitchshift">
            <title>PitchShift</title>
            <paragraph>This effect allows the adjustment of the signal's pitch independently of its
                speed. All frequencies can be increased/decreased with minimal effect on
                transients. PitchShift can be useful to create unusually high or deep voices.
                Do note that altering pitch can sound unnatural when pushed outside of a
                narrow window.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="record" names="record">
            <title>Record</title>
            <paragraph>The Record effect allows the user to record sound from a microphone.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="reverb" names="reverb">
            <title>Reverb</title>
            <paragraph>Reverb simulates rooms of different sizes. It has adjustable parameters that can
                be tweaked to obtain the sound of a specific room. Reverb is commonly outputted
                from <reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_area3d#class-area3d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Area3Ds</inline></reference>
                (see <reference internal="True" refuri="audio_streams#doc-audio-streams-reverb-buses"><inline classes="std std-ref">Reverb buses</inline></reference>), or to apply
                a "chamber" feel to all sounds.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="spectrumanalyzer" names="spectrumanalyzer">
            <title>SpectrumAnalyzer</title>
            <paragraph>This effect doesn't alter audio, instead, you add this effect to buses you want
                a spectrum analysis of. This would typically be used for audio visualization.
                Visualizing voices can be a great way to draw attention to them without just
                increasing their volume.
                A demo project using this can be found <reference name="here" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-demo-projects/tree/master/audio/spectrum">here</reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="stereoenhance" names="stereoenhance">
            <title>StereoEnhance</title>
            <paragraph>This effect uses a few algorithms to enhance a signal's stereo width.</paragraph>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
