<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/audio/audio_buses.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-audio-buses"></target>
    <section dupnames="audio\ buses" ids="audio-buses doc-audio-buses" names="doc_audio_buses">
        <title>Audio buses</title>
        <section ids="introduction" names="introduction">
            <title>Introduction</title>
            <paragraph>Godot's audio processing code has been written with games in mind, with the aim
                of achieving an optimal balance between performance and sound quality.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Godot's audio engine allows any number of audio buses to be created and any
                number of effect processors can be added to each bus. Only the hardware of the
                device running your game will limit the number of buses and effects that can be
                used before performance starts to suffer.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="decibel-scale" names="decibel\ scale">
            <title>Decibel scale</title>
            <paragraph>Godot's sound interface is designed to meet the expectations of sound design
                professionals. To this end, it primarily uses the decibel scale.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>For those unfamiliar with it, it can be explained with a few facts:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>The decibel (dB) scale is a relative scale. It represents the ratio of
                        sound power by using 20 times the base 10 logarithm of the ratio
                        (20 × log<subscript>10</subscript>(P/P<subscript>0</subscript>)).</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>For every 6 dB, sound amplitude doubles or halves. 12 dB represents a factor
                        of 4, 18 dB a factor of 8, 20 dB a factor of 10, 40 dB a factor of 100, etc.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Since the scale is logarithmic, true zero (no audio) can't be represented.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>0 dB is the maximum amplitude possible in a digital audio system.
                        This limit is not the human limit, but a limit from the sound hardware.
                        Audio with amplitudes that are too high to be represented properly below 0 dB
                        create a kind of distortion called <emphasis>clipping</emphasis>.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>To avoid clipping, your sound mix should be arranged so that the output of the
                        <emphasis>master bus</emphasis> (more on that later) never exceeds 0 dB.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Every 6 dB below the 0 dB limit, sound energy is <emphasis>halved</emphasis>.
                        It means the sound volume at -6 dB is half as loud as 0dB.
                        -12 dB is half as loud as -6 dB and so on.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>When working with decibels, sound is considered no longer audible
                        between -60 dB and -80 dB. This makes your working range generally
                        between -60 dB and 0 dB.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>This can take a bit getting used to, but it's friendlier in the end
                and will allow you to communicate better with audio professionals.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section dupnames="audio\ buses" ids="id1">
            <title>Audio buses</title>
            <paragraph>Audio buses can be found in the bottom panel of the Godot editor:</paragraph>
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses1.webp'}" original_uri="img/audio_buses1.webp" uri="tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses1.webp"></image>
            <paragraph>An <emphasis>audio bus</emphasis> (also called an <emphasis>audio channel</emphasis>) can be considered a place that
                audio is channeled through on the way to playback through a device's speakers.
                Audio data can be <emphasis>modified</emphasis> and <emphasis>re-routed</emphasis> by an audio bus. An audio bus
                has a VU meter (the bars that light up when sound is played) which indicates the
                amplitude of the signal passing through.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The leftmost bus is the <emphasis>master bus</emphasis>. This bus outputs the mix to your speakers
                so, as mentioned in the <emphasis>Decibel scale</emphasis> section above, make sure that your mix
                level doesn't reach 0 dB in this bus. The rest of the audio buses can be
                flexibly routed. After modifying the sound, they send it to another bus to
                the left. The destination bus can be specified for each of the non-master audio
                buses. Routing always passes audio from buses on the right to buses further
                to the left. This avoids infinite routing loops.</paragraph>
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses2.webp'}" original_uri="img/audio_buses2.webp" uri="tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses2.webp"></image>
            <paragraph>In the above image, the output of <emphasis>Bus 2</emphasis> has been routed to the <emphasis>Master</emphasis> bus.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="playback-of-audio-through-a-bus" names="playback\ of\ audio\ through\ a\ bus">
            <title>Playback of audio through a bus</title>
            <paragraph>To test passing audio to a bus, create an AudioStreamPlayer node, load an
                AudioStream and select a target bus for playback:</paragraph>
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses3.webp'}" original_uri="img/audio_buses3.webp" uri="tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses3.webp"></image>
            <paragraph>Finally, toggle the <strong>Playing</strong> property to <strong>On</strong> and sound will flow.</paragraph>
            <seealso>
                <paragraph>You may also be interested in reading about <reference internal="True" refuri="audio_streams#doc-audio-streams"><inline classes="std std-ref">Audio streams</inline></reference> now.</paragraph>
            </seealso>
        </section>
        <section ids="adding-effects" names="adding\ effects">
            <title>Adding effects</title>
            <warning>
                <paragraph>This feature is not supported on the web platform if the AudioStreamPlayer's
                    playback mode is set to <strong>Sample</strong>, which is the default. It will only work if the
                    playback mode is set to <strong>Stream</strong>, at the cost of increased latency if threads
                    are not enabled.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>See <reference internal="True" refuri="../export/exporting_for_web#doc-exporting-for-web-audio-playback"><inline classes="std std-ref">Audio playback in the Exporting for the Web documentation</inline></reference>
                    for details.</paragraph>
            </warning>
            <paragraph>Audio buses can contain all sorts of effects. These effects modify the sound in
                one way or another and are applied in order.</paragraph>
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses4.webp'}" original_uri="img/audio_buses4.webp" uri="tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses4.webp"></image>
            <paragraph>For information on what each effect does, see <reference internal="True" refuri="audio_effects#doc-audio-effects"><inline classes="std std-ref">Audio effects</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="automatic-bus-disabling" names="automatic\ bus\ disabling">
            <title>Automatic bus disabling</title>
            <paragraph>There is no need to disable buses manually when not in use. Godot detects
                that the bus has been silent for a few seconds and disables it (including
                all effects).</paragraph>
            <figure ids="id2">
                <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses5.webp'}" original_uri="img/audio_buses5.webp" uri="tutorials/audio/img/audio_buses5.webp"></image>
                <caption>Disabled buses have a blue VU meter instead of a red-green one.</caption>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section ids="bus-rearrangement" names="bus\ rearrangement">
            <title>Bus rearrangement</title>
            <paragraph>Stream Players use bus names to identify a bus, which allows adding, removing
                and moving buses around while the reference to them is kept. However, if a bus
                is renamed, the reference will be lost and the Stream Player will output
                to Master. This system was chosen because rearranging buses is a more common
                process than renaming them.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="default-bus-layout" names="default\ bus\ layout">
            <title>Default bus layout</title>
            <paragraph>The default bus layout is automatically saved to the
                <literal>res://default_bus_layout.tres</literal> file. Custom bus arrangements can be saved
                and loaded from disk.</paragraph>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
