<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/editor/customizing_editor.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-customizing-editor"></target>
    <section ids="customizing-the-interface doc-customizing-editor" names="customizing\ the\ interface doc_customizing_editor">
        <title>Customizing the interface</title>
        <paragraph>Godot's interface lives in a single window by default. Since Godot 4.0, you can
            split several elements to separate windows to better make use of multi-monitor
            setups.</paragraph>
        <target refid="doc-customizing-editor-moving-docks"></target>
        <section ids="moving-and-resizing-docks doc-customizing-editor-moving-docks" names="moving\ and\ resizing\ docks doc_customizing_editor_moving_docks">
            <title>Moving and resizing docks</title>
            <paragraph>Click and drag on the edge of any dock or panel to resize it horizontally or
                vertically:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id1">
                <image alt="Resizing a dock in the editor" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/editor/img/editor_ui_resize_dock.webp'}" original_uri="img/editor_ui_resize_dock.webp" uri="tutorials/editor/img/editor_ui_resize_dock.webp"></image>
                <caption>Resizing a dock in the editor</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>Click the "3 vertical dots" icon at the top of any dock to change its location,
                or split it to a separate window by choosing <strong>Make Floating</strong> in the submenu that appears:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id2">
                <image alt="Moving a dock in the editor" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/editor/img/editor_ui_move_dock.webp'}" original_uri="img/editor_ui_move_dock.webp" uri="tutorials/editor/img/editor_ui_move_dock.webp"></image>
                <caption>Moving a dock in the editor</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>To move a floating dock back to the editor window, close the dock window using
                the <strong>×</strong> button in the top-right corner of the window (or in the top-left
                corner on macOS). Alternatively, you can press <literal classes="kbd">Alt + F4</literal> while the split
                window is focused.</paragraph>
            <comment xml:space="preserve">This page lacks information about:

- Useful editor settings or sections of the settings window that are
  relevant to customizing the interface.
- Layouts</comment>
        </section>
        <section ids="splitting-the-script-or-shader-editor-to-its-own-window" names="splitting\ the\ script\ or\ shader\ editor\ to\ its\ own\ window">
            <title>Splitting the script or shader editor to its own window</title>
            <note>
                <paragraph>This feature is only available on platforms that support spawning multiple
                    windows: Windows, macOS and Linux.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>This feature is also not available if <strong>Single Window Mode</strong> is enabled in
                    the Editor Settings.</paragraph>
            </note>
            <paragraph>Since Godot 4.1, you can split the script or shader editor to its own window.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>To split the script editor to its own window, click the corresponding button in
                the top-right corner of the script editor:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id3">
                <image alt="Splitting the script editor to its own window" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/editor/img/editor_ui_split_script_editor.webp'}" original_uri="img/editor_ui_split_script_editor.webp" uri="tutorials/editor/img/editor_ui_split_script_editor.webp"></image>
                <caption>Splitting the script editor to its own window</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>To split the shader editor to its own window, click the corresponding button in
                the top-right corner of the script editor:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id4">
                <image alt="Splitting the shader editor to its own window" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/editor/img/editor_ui_split_shader_editor.webp'}" original_uri="img/editor_ui_split_shader_editor.webp" uri="tutorials/editor/img/editor_ui_split_shader_editor.webp"></image>
                <caption>Splitting the shader editor to its own window</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>To go back to the previous state (with the script/shader editor embedded in the
                editor window), close the split window using the <strong>×</strong> button in the top-right
                corner of the window (or in the top-left corner on macOS). Alternatively, you
                can press <literal classes="kbd">Alt + F4</literal> while the split window is focused.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="customizing-editor-layouts" names="customizing\ editor\ layouts">
            <title>Customizing editor layouts</title>
            <paragraph>You may want to save and load a dock configuration depending on the kind of task
                you're working on. For instance, when working on animating a character, it may
                be more convenient to have docks laid out in a different fashion compared to
                when you're designing a level.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>For this purpose, Godot provides a way to save and restore editor layouts.
                Before saving a layout, make changes to the docks you'd like to save. The
                following changes are persisted to the saved layout:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Moving a dock.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Resizing a dock.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Making a dock floating.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Changing a floating dock's position or size.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>FileSystem dock properties: split mode, display mode, sorting order, file list
                        display mode, selected paths and unfolded paths.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <note>
                <paragraph>Splitting the script or shader editor to its own window is <emphasis>not</emphasis> persisted
                    as part of a layout.</paragraph>
            </note>
            <paragraph>After making changes, open the <strong>Editor</strong> menu at the top of the editor then
                choose <strong>Editor Layouts &gt; Save</strong>. Enter a name for the layout, then click
                <strong>Save</strong>. If you've already saved an editor layout, you can choose to override
                an existing layout using the list.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>After making changes, open the <strong>Editor</strong> menu at the top of the editor then
                choose <strong>Editor Layouts</strong>. In the dropdown list, you will see a list of saved
                editor layouts, plus <strong>Default</strong> which is a hardcoded editor layout that can't
                be removed. The default layout matches a fresh Godot installation with no
                changes made to the docks' positions and sizes, and no floating docks.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>You can remove a layout using the <strong>Delete</strong> option in the <strong>Editor Layouts</strong>
                dropdown.</paragraph>
            <tip>
                <paragraph>If you name the saved layout <literal>Default</literal> (case-sensitive), the default
                    editor layout will be overwritten. Note that the <literal>Default</literal> does not appear
                    in the list of layouts to overwrite until you overwrite it once, but you can
                    still write its name manually.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>You can go back to the standard default layout by removing the <literal>Default</literal>
                    layout after overriding it. (This option does not appear if you haven't
                    overridden the default layout yet.)</paragraph>
            </tip>
            <paragraph>Editor layouts are saved to a file named <literal>editor_layouts.cfg</literal> in
                the configuration path of the <reference internal="True" refuri="../io/data_paths#doc-data-paths-editor-data-paths"><inline classes="std std-ref">Editor data paths</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="customizing-editor-settings" names="customizing\ editor\ settings">
            <title>Customizing editor settings</title>
            <paragraph>In the <strong>Editor</strong> menu at the top of the editor, you can find an <strong>Editor
                    Settings</strong> option. This opens a window similar to the Project Settings, but with
                settings used by the editor. These settings are shared across all projects and
                are not saved in the project files.</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id5">
                <image alt="The Editor Settings window" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/editor/img/editor_settings.webp'}" original_uri="img/editor_settings.webp" uri="tutorials/editor/img/editor_settings.webp"></image>
                <caption>The Editor Settings window</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>Some commonly changed settings are:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Interface &gt; Editor &gt; Editor Language:</strong> Controls the language the editor
                        displays in. To make English tutorials easier to follow, you may want to
                        change this to English so that menu names are identical to names referred to
                        by tutorials. The language can also be changed in the top-right corner of the
                        project manager.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Interface &gt; Editor &gt; Display Scale:</strong> Controls how large UI elements display
                        on screen. The default <strong>Auto</strong> setting finds a suitable value based on your
                        display's DPI and resolution. Due to engine limitations, it only takes the
                        display-provided scaling factor on macOS, not on Windows or Linux.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Interface &gt; Editor &gt; Single Window Mode:</strong> If enabled, this forces the
                        editor to use a single window. This disables certain features such as
                        splitting the script/shaders editor to their own window. Single-window mode
                        can be more stable, especially on Linux when using Wayland.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Interface &gt; Theme &gt; Preset:</strong> The editor theme preset to use. The <strong>Light</strong> theme
                        preset may be easier to read if you're outdoors or in a room with sunlight.
                        The <strong>Black (OLED)</strong> preset can reduce power consumption on OLED displays,
                        which are increasingly common in laptops and phones/tablets.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>FileSystem &gt; Directories &gt; Autoscan Project Path:</strong> This can be set to a
                        folder path that will be automatically scanned for projects in the project
                        manager every time it starts.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>FileSystem &gt; Directories &gt; Default Project Path:</strong> Controls the default
                        location where new projects are created in the project manager.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Editors &gt; 3D &gt; Emulate Numpad:</strong> This allows using the top row 0-9 keys in
                        the 3D editor as their equivalent numpad keys. It's recommended to enable this
                        option if you don't have a number pad on your keyboard.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Editors &gt; 3D &gt; Emulate 3 Button Mouse:</strong> This allows using the pan, zoom and
                        orbit modifiers in the 3D editor even when not holding down any mouse button.
                        It's recommended to enable this option if you're using a trackpad.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>See the <reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_editorsettings#class-editorsettings"><inline classes="std std-ref">EditorSettings</inline></reference> class reference for a complete description
                of most editor settings. You can also hover an editor setting's name with the
                mouse in the Editor Settings to show its description.</paragraph>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
