<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/2d/introduction_to_2d.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-introduction-to-2d"></target>
    <section ids="introduction-to-2d doc-introduction-to-2d" names="introduction\ to\ 2d doc_introduction_to_2d">
        <title>Introduction to 2D</title>
        <paragraph>Godot's 2D game development tools include a dedicated 2D rendering engine, physics system,
            and features tailored specifically for creating 2D experiences. You can efficiently design
            levels with the TileMap system, animate characters with 2D sprite or Cutout animation,
            and leverage 2D lighting for dynamic scene illumination. The built-in 2D particle system
            allows you to create complex visual effects, and Godot also supports custom shaders to
            enhance your graphics. These features, combined with Godot's accessibility and
            flexibility, provide a solid foundation for creating engaging 2D games.</paragraph>
        <figure ids="id1">
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/2d_platformer_demo.webp'}" original_uri="img/2d_platformer_demo.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/2d_platformer_demo.webp"></image>
            <caption>2D Platformer Demo available on the Asset Library.</caption>
        </figure>
        <paragraph>This page will show you the 2D workspace and how you can get to know it.</paragraph>
        <tip>
            <paragraph>If you would like to get an introduction to 3D, see <reference internal="True" refuri="../3d/introduction_to_3d#doc-introduction-to-3d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Introduction to 3D</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
        </tip>
        <section ids="d-workspace" names="2d\ workspace">
            <title>2D workspace</title>
            <paragraph>You will use the 2D workspace to work with 2D scenes, design levels, or create user
                interfaces.
                To switch to the 2D workspace, you can either select a 2D node from the scene tree,
                or use the workspace selector located at the top edge of the editor:</paragraph>
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/2d_editor_viewport.webp'}" original_uri="img/2d_editor_viewport.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/2d_editor_viewport.webp"></image>
            <paragraph>Similar to 3D, you can use the tabs below the workspace selector to change between currently
                opened scenes or create a new one using the plus (+) button. The left and right docks should
                be familiar from <reference internal="True" refuri="../editor/index#toc-editor-interface"><inline classes="std std-ref">editor introduction</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Below the scene selector is the main toolbar, and beneath the main toolbar
                is the 2D viewport.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>You can drag and drop compatible nodes from the FileSystem dock to add them to the
                viewport as nodes.
                Dragging and dropping adds the dragged node as a sibling of the selected node
                (if the root node is selected, adds as a child).
                Keeping <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal> pressed when dropping adds the node as a child of the selected node.
                Holding <literal classes="kbd">Alt</literal> when dropping adds the node as a child of the root node.
                If <literal classes="kbd">Alt + Shift</literal> is held when dropping, the node type can be selected if
                applicable.</paragraph>
            <section ids="main-toolbar" names="main\ toolbar">
                <title>Main toolbar</title>
                <paragraph>Some buttons in the main toolbar are the same as those in the 3D workspace. A brief explanation
                    is given with the shortcut if the mouse cursor is hovered over a button for one second.
                    Some buttons may have additional functionality if another keypress is performed.
                    A recap of main functionality of each button with its default shortcut is provided below
                    from left to right:</paragraph>
                <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/2d_toolbar.webp'}" original_uri="img/2d_toolbar.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/2d_toolbar.webp"></image>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Select Mode</strong> (<literal classes="kbd">Q</literal>): Allows selection of nodes in the viewport. Left clicking on a node
                            in the viewport selects it.
                            Left clicking and dragging a rectangle selects all nodes within the rectangle's boundaries,
                            once released.
                            Holding <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal> while selecting adds more nodes to the selection.
                            Clicking on a selected node while holding <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal> deselects the node.
                            In this mode, you can drag the selected node(s) to move, press <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl</literal> to switch to the
                            rotation mode temporarily, or use the red circles to scale it. If multiple nodes are
                            selected, only movement and rotation are possible. In this mode, rotation and scaling
                            will not use the snapping options if snapping is enabled.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Move Mode</strong> (<literal classes="kbd">W</literal>): Enables move (or translate) mode for the selected nodes. See
                            <reference internal="True" refid="doc-introduction-to-2d-the-viewport"><inline classes="std std-ref">2D Viewport</inline></reference> for more details.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Rotate Mode</strong> (<literal classes="kbd">E</literal>): Enables rotation mode for the selected nodes. See
                            <reference internal="True" refid="doc-introduction-to-2d-the-viewport"><inline classes="std std-ref">2D Viewport</inline></reference> for more details.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Scale Mode</strong> (<literal classes="kbd">S</literal>): Enables scaling and displays scaling gizmos in both
                            axes for the selected node(s). See <reference internal="True" refid="doc-introduction-to-2d-the-viewport"><inline classes="std std-ref">2D Viewport</inline></reference> for more details.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Show list of selectable nodes at position clicked</strong>: As the description suggests,
                            this provides a list of selectable nodes at the clicked position as a context menu, if
                            there is more than one node in the clicked area.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Rotation pivot</strong>: Sets the rotation pivot to rotate node(s) around.
                            An added node has its rotation pivot at <literal>x: 0</literal>, <literal>y: 0</literal>, by default, with
                            exceptions. For example, the default pivot for a <reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_sprite2d#class-sprite2d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Sprite2D</inline></reference> is its
                            center if the <literal>centered</literal> property is set to <literal>true</literal>. If you would like to change the
                            rotation pivot of a node, click this button and choose a new location by left clicking.
                            The node rotates considering this point. If you have multiple nodes selected, this icon
                            will add a temporary pivot to be used commonly by all selected nodes. Pressing <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal>
                            and clicking this button will create the pivot at the center of selected nodes. If any of
                            the snap options are enabled, the pivot will also snap to them when dragged.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Pan Mode</strong> (<literal classes="kbd">G</literal>): Allows you to navigate in the viewport without accidentally selecting any nodes.
                            In other modes, you can also hold <literal classes="kbd">Space</literal> and drag with the left mouse button to do the same.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Ruler Mode</strong>: After enabling, click on the viewport to display the current global
                            x and y coordinates. Dragging from a position to another one measures the distance in pixels.
                            If you drag diagonally, it will draw a triangle and show the separate distances in terms
                            of x, y, and total distance to the target, including the angles to the axes in degrees.
                            The <literal classes="kbd">R</literal> key activates the ruler. If snapping is enabled, it also displays the
                            measurements in terms of grid count:</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
                <figure ids="id2">
                    <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/2d_ruler_with_snap.webp'}" original_uri="img/2d_ruler_with_snap.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/2d_ruler_with_snap.webp"></image>
                    <caption>Using ruler with snapping enabled.</caption>
                </figure>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Use Smart Snap</strong>: Toggles smart snapping for move, rotate, and scale modes; and
                            the rotation pivot. Customize it using the three-dot menu next to the snap tools.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Use Grid Snap</strong>: Toggles snapping to grid for move and scale mode, rotation pivot,
                            and the ruler. Customize it using the three-dot menu next to the snap tools.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
                <paragraph>You can customize the grid settings so that move mode, rotate mode, scale mode, ruler,
                    and rotation pivot uses snapping.
                    Use the three-dot menu for this:</paragraph>
                <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/2d_snapping_options_menu.webp'}" original_uri="img/2d_snapping_options_menu.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/2d_snapping_options_menu.webp"></image>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Use Rotation Snap</strong>: Toggles snapping using the configured rotation setting.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Use Scale Snap</strong>: Toggles snapping using the configured scaling step setting.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Snap Relative</strong>: Toggles the usage of snapping based on the selected node's current
                            transform values. For example, if the grids are set to 32x32 pixels and if the selected node
                            is located at <literal>x: 1, y: 1</literal>, then, enabling this option will temporarily shift the grids by
                            <literal>x: 1, y: 1</literal>.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Use Pixel Snap</strong>: Toggles the use of subpixels for snapping. If enabled, the position values
                            will be integers, disabling will enable subpixel movement as decimal values. For the runtime
                            property, consider checking <title_reference>Project Settings &gt; Rendering &gt; 2D &gt; Snapping</title_reference> property for
                            Node2D nodes, and <title_reference>Project Settings &gt; GUI &gt; General &gt; Snap Controls to Pixels</title_reference> for
                            Control nodes.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Smart Snapping</strong>: Provides a set of options to snap to specific positions if they are enabled:</paragraph>
                        <bullet_list bullet="-">
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Snap to Parent: Snaps to parent's edges. For example, scaling a child control node while
                                    this is enabled will snap to the boundaries of the parent.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Snap to Node Anchor: Snaps to the node's anchor. For example, if anchors of a control
                                    node is positioned at different positions, enabling this will snap to the sides and
                                    corners of the anchor.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Snap to Node Sides: Snaps to the node's sides, such as for the rotation pivot or anchor
                                    positioning.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Snap to Node Center: Snaps to the node's center, such as for the rotation pivot or
                                    anchor positioning.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Snap to Other Nodes: Snaps to other nodes while moving or scaling. Useful to align nodes
                                    in the editor.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Snap to Guides: Snaps to custom guides drawn using the horizontal or vertical ruler. More
                                    on the ruler and guides below.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                        </bullet_list>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
                <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/2d_snapping_options.webp'}" original_uri="img/2d_snapping_options.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/2d_snapping_options.webp"></image>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Configure Snap</strong>: Opens the window shown above, offering a set of snapping parameters.</paragraph>
                        <bullet_list bullet="-">
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Grid Offset: Allows you to shift grids with respect to the origin. <literal>x</literal> and <literal>y</literal> can
                                    be adjusted separately.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Grid Step: The distance between each grid in pixels. <literal>x</literal> and <literal>y</literal> can be adjusted separately.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Primary Line Every: The number of grids in-between to draw infinite lines as indication of
                                    main lines.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Rotation Offset: Sets the offset to shift rotational snapping.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Rotation Step: Defines the snapping degree. E.g., 15 means the node will rotate and snap
                                    at multiples of 15 degrees if rotation snap is enabled and the rotate mode is used.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Scale Step: Determines the scaling increment factor. For example, if it is 0.1, it will
                                    change the scaling at 0.1 steps if scaling snap is enabled and the scaling mode is used.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                        </bullet_list>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Lock selected nodes</strong> (<literal classes="kbd">Ctrl + L</literal>). Locks the selected nodes, preventing selection and movement in the
                            viewport. Clicking the button again (or using <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl + Shift + L</literal>) unlocks the selected
                            nodes. Locked nodes can only be selected in the scene tree.
                            They can easily be identified by a padlock next to their node names in the scene tree.
                            Clicking on this padlock also unlocks the nodes.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Group selected nodes</strong> (<literal classes="kbd">Ctrl + G</literal>). This allows selection of the root node if any
                            of the children are selected. Using <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl + G</literal> ungroups them. Additionally, clicking
                            the ungroup button in the scene tree performs the same action.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Skeleton Options</strong>: Provides options to work with Skeleton2D and Bone2D.</paragraph>
                        <bullet_list bullet="-">
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Show Bones: Toggles the visibility of bones for the selected node.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>Make Bone2D Node(s) from Node(s): Converts selected node(s) into Bone2D.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                        </bullet_list>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
                <seealso>
                    <paragraph>To learn more about Skeletons, see <reference internal="True" refuri="../animation/cutout_animation#doc-cutout-animation"><inline classes="std std-ref">Cutout animation</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
                </seealso>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>View</strong> menu: Provides options to control the viewport view. Since its options
                            depend heavily on the viewport, it is covered in the <reference internal="True" refid="doc-introduction-to-2d-the-viewport"><inline classes="std std-ref">2D Viewport</inline></reference>
                            section.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
                <paragraph>Next to the View menu, additional buttons may be visible. In the toolbar image
                    at the beginning of this chapter, an additional <emphasis>Sprite2D</emphasis> button appears because a
                    Sprite2D is selected. This menu provides some quick actions and tools to
                    work on a specific node or selection. For example, while drawing a polygon, it
                    provides buttons to add, modify, or remove points.</paragraph>
            </section>
            <section ids="coordinate-system" names="coordinate\ system">
                <title>Coordinate system</title>
                <paragraph>In the 2D editor, unlike 3D, there are only two axes: <literal>x</literal> and <literal>y</literal>. Also, the viewing
                    angle is fixed.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>In the viewport, you will see two lines in two colors going across the screen infinitely:
                    red for the x-axis, and green for the y-axis.
                    In Godot, going right and down are positive directions.
                    Where these two lines intersect is the origin: <literal>x: 0, y: 0</literal>.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>A root node will have its origin at this position once added.
                    Switching to the <title_reference>move</title_reference> or <title_reference>scale</title_reference> modes after selecting a node will display the gizmos at the
                    node's offset position.
                    The gizmos will point to the positive directions of the x and y axes.
                    In the move mode, you can drag the green line to move only in the <literal>y</literal> axis.
                    Similarly, you can hold the red line to move only in the <literal>x</literal> axis.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>In the scale mode, the gizmos will have a square shape. You can hold and drag the green and
                    red squares to scale the nodes in the <literal>y</literal> or <literal>x</literal> axes.
                    Dragging in a negative direction flips the node horizontally or vertically.</paragraph>
                <target refid="doc-introduction-to-2d-the-viewport"></target>
            </section>
            <section ids="d-viewport doc-introduction-to-2d-the-viewport" names="2d\ viewport doc_introduction_to_2d_the_viewport">
                <title>2D Viewport</title>
                <paragraph>The viewport will be the area you spend the most time if you plan to design levels or user
                    interfaces visually:</paragraph>
                <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/2d_editor_viewport_with_viewmenu.webp'}" original_uri="img/2d_editor_viewport_with_viewmenu.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/2d_editor_viewport_with_viewmenu.webp"></image>
                <paragraph>Middle-clicking and dragging the mouse will pan the view.
                    The scrollbars on the right or bottom of the viewport also move the view.
                    Alternatively, the <literal classes="kbd">G</literal> or <literal classes="kbd">Space</literal> keys can be used.
                    If you enable <title_reference>Editor Settings &gt; Editors &gt; Panning &gt; Simple Panning</title_reference>, you can activate
                    panning directly with <literal classes="kbd">Space</literal> only, without requiring dragging.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>The viewport has buttons on the top-left.
                    <strong>Center View</strong> centers the selected node(s) in the screen. Useful if you have a large scene
                    with many nodes, and want to see the node selected in the scene tree.
                    Next to it are the zoom controls. <strong>-</strong> zooms out, <strong>+</strong> zooms in, and clicking on the number
                    with percentage defaults to 100%.
                    Alternatively, you can use middle-mouse scrolling to zoom in (scroll up) and out (scroll down).</paragraph>
                <paragraph>The black bars at the viewport's left and top edges are the <strong>rulers</strong>. You can use them to
                    orient yourself in the viewport.
                    By default, the rulers will display the pixel coordinates of the viewport, numbered at
                    100 pixel steps. Changing the zoom factor will change the shown values.
                    Enabling <title_reference>Grid Snap</title_reference> or changing the snapping options will update the ruler's scaling and
                    the shown values.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>You can also create multiple custom guides to help you make measurements or align
                    nodes with them:</paragraph>
                <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/2d_editor_guidelines.webp'}" original_uri="img/2d_editor_guidelines.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/2d_editor_guidelines.webp"></image>
                <paragraph>If you have at least one node in the scene, you can create guides by dragging from the horizontal
                    or vertical ruler towards the viewport. A purple guide will appear, showing its position, and will
                    remain there when you release the mouse. You can create both horizontal and vertical guides
                    simultaneously by dragging from the gray square at the rulers' intersection. Guides can be
                    repositioned by dragging them back to their respective rulers, and they can be removed by
                    dragging them all the way back to the ruler.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>You can also enable snapping to the created guides using the <title_reference>Smart Snap</title_reference> menu.</paragraph>
                <note>
                    <paragraph>If you cannot create a line, or do not see previously created guides, make sure that
                        they are visible by checking the <title_reference>View</title_reference> menu of the viewport. <literal classes="kbd">Y</literal> toggles their visibility,
                        by default. Also, make sure you have at least one node in the scene.</paragraph>
                </note>
                <paragraph>Depending on the tool chosen in the toolbar, left-clicking will have a primary action in the
                    viewport.
                    For example, the <title_reference>Select Mode</title_reference> will select the left-clicked node in the viewport.
                    Sometimes, left-clicking can be combined with a modifier (e.g., <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl</literal>, or <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal>) to
                    perform secondary actions.
                    For example, keeping <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal> pressed while dragging a node in the Select or Move modes will
                    try to snap the node in a single axis while moving.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>Right clicking in the viewport provides two options to create a node or instantiate a scene
                    at the chosen position.
                    If at least one node is selected, right clicking also provides the option to move the selected
                    node(s) to this position.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>Viewport has a <strong>View</strong> menu which provides several options to change the look of the viewport:</paragraph>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Grid</strong>: Allows you to show grids all the time, only when using snapping, or not at all. You
                            can also toggle them with the provided option.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Show Helpers</strong>: Toggles the temporary display of an outline of the node, with the previous
                            transform properties (position, scaling, or rotation) if a transform operation has been
                            initiated. For <title_reference>Control</title_reference> nodes, it also shows the sizing parameters. Useful to see the deltas.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Show Rulers</strong>: Toggles the visibility of horizontal and vertical rulers. See
                            <reference internal="True" refid="doc-introduction-to-2d-the-viewport"><inline classes="std std-ref">2D Viewport</inline></reference> more on rulers.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Show Guides</strong>: Toggles the visibility of created guides. See
                            <reference internal="True" refid="doc-introduction-to-2d-the-viewport"><inline classes="std std-ref">2D Viewport</inline></reference> for on how to create them.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Show Origin</strong>: Toggles the display of the green and red origin lines drawn at <literal>x: 0, y: 0</literal>.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Show Viewport</strong>: Toggles the visibility of the game's default
                            viewport, indicated by an indigo-colored rectangle. It is also the default window size on desktop
                            platforms, which can be changed by going to <title_reference>Project Settings &gt; Display &gt; Window &gt; Size</title_reference> and
                            setting <title_reference>Viewport Width</title_reference> and <title_reference>Viewport Height</title_reference>.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Gizmos</strong>: Toggles the visibility of <title_reference>Position</title_reference> (shown with cross icon), <title_reference>Lock</title_reference>
                            (shown with padlock), <title_reference>Groups</title_reference> (shown with two squares), and <title_reference>Transformation</title_reference> (shown with
                            green and red lines) indicators.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Center Selection</strong>: The same as the <strong>Center View</strong> button inside the viewport. Centers the selected
                            node(s) in the view. <literal classes="kbd">F</literal> is the default shortcut.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Frame to Selection</strong>: Similar to <title_reference>Center Selection</title_reference>, but also changes the zoom factor to fit the
                            contents in the screen. <literal classes="kbd">Shift + F</literal> is the default shortcut.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Clear Guides</strong>: Deletes all guides from the screen. You will need to recreate them if
                            you plan to use them later.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Preview Canvas Scale</strong>: Toggles the preview for scaling of canvas in the editor when the zoom
                            factor or view of the viewport changes. Useful to see how the controls will look like after scaling
                            and moving, without running the game.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Preview Theme</strong>: Allows to choose from the available themes to change the look of control items
                            in the editor, without requiring to run the game.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section ids="node2d-and-control-node" names="node2d\ and\ control\ node">
            <title>Node2D and Control node</title>
            <paragraph><reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_canvasitem#class-canvasitem"><inline classes="std std-ref">CanvasItem</inline></reference> is the base node for 2D. <reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_node2d#class-node2d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Node2D</inline></reference> is the base node
                for 2D game objects, and <reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_control#class-control"><inline classes="std std-ref">Control</inline></reference> is the base node
                for everything GUI. For 3D, Godot uses the <reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_node3d#class-node3d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Node3D</inline></reference> node.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="d-in-2d" names="3d\ in\ 2d">
            <title>3D in 2D</title>
            <paragraph>It is possible to display 3D scenes in 2D screen, You can see this in the demo <reference name="3D in 2D Viewport" refuri="https://godotengine.org/asset-library/asset/2804">3D in 2D Viewport</reference>.</paragraph>
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/3d_in_2d_demo_editor.webp'}" original_uri="img/3d_in_2d_demo_editor.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/3d_in_2d_demo_editor.webp"></image>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
