<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/2d/using_tilemaps.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-using-tilemaps"></target>
    <section ids="using-tilemaps doc-using-tilemaps" names="using\ tilemaps doc_using_tilemaps">
        <title>Using TileMaps</title>
        <seealso>
            <paragraph>This page assumes you have created or downloaded a TileSet already. If not,
                please read <reference internal="True" refuri="using_tilesets#doc-using-tilesets"><inline classes="std std-ref">Using TileSets</inline></reference> first as you will need a TileSet
                to create a TileMap.</paragraph>
        </seealso>
        <section ids="introduction" names="introduction">
            <title>Introduction</title>
            <paragraph>A tilemap is a grid of tiles used to create a game's layout. There are several
                benefits to using <reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_tilemaplayer#class-tilemaplayer"><inline classes="std std-ref">TileMapLayer</inline></reference> nodes to design your levels.
                First, they make it possible to draw the layout by "painting" the tiles onto a
                grid, which is much faster than placing individual <reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_sprite2d#class-sprite2d"><inline classes="std std-ref">Sprite2D</inline></reference>
                nodes one by one. Second, they allow for much larger levels because they are
                optimized for drawing large numbers of tiles. Finally, you can add collision,
                occlusion, and navigation shapes to tiles, adding greater functionality to
                the TileMap.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="specifying-the-tileset-in-the-tilemaplayer" names="specifying\ the\ tileset\ in\ the\ tilemaplayer">
            <title>Specifying the TileSet in the TileMapLayer</title>
            <paragraph>If you've followed the previous page on <reference internal="True" refuri="using_tilesets#doc-using-tilesets"><inline classes="std std-ref">Using TileSets</inline></reference>, you should
                have a TileSet resource that is built into the TileMapLayer node. This is good for
                prototyping, but in a real world project, you will generally have multiple
                levels reusing the same tileset.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The recommended way to reuse the same TileSet in several TileMapLayer nodes is to save
                the TileSet to an external resource. To do so, click the dropdown next to the TileSet
                resource and choose <strong>Save</strong>:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id1">
                <image alt="Saving the built-in TileSet resource to an external resource file" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_save_tileset_to_resource.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_save_tileset_to_resource.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_save_tileset_to_resource.webp"></image>
                <caption>Saving the built-in TileSet resource to an external resource file</caption>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section ids="multiple-tilemaplayers-and-settings" names="multiple\ tilemaplayers\ and\ settings">
            <title>Multiple TileMapLayers and settings</title>
            <paragraph>When working with tilemaps it's generally advised that you use multiple TileMapLayer
                nodes when appropriate. Using multiple layers can be advantageous, for example,
                this allows you to distinguish foreground tiles from background tiles for better
                organization. You can place one tile per layer at a given location, which allows you
                to overlap several tiles together if you have more than one layer.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Each TileMapLayer node has several properties you can adjust:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Enabled:</strong> If <literal>true</literal>, the layer is visible in the editor and when running
                        the project.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>TileSet</strong> The tileset used by the TileMapLayer node.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <section ids="rendering" names="rendering">
                <title>Rendering</title>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Y Sort Origin:</strong> The vertical offset to use for Y-sorting on each tile (in pixels).
                            Only effective if <strong>Y Sort Enabled</strong> under CanvasItem settings is <literal>true</literal>.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>X Draw Order Reversed</strong> Reverses the order tiles are drawn on the X axis. Requires
                            that <strong>Y Sort Enabled</strong> under CanvasItem settings is <literal>true</literal>.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Rendering Quadrant Size</strong> A quadrant is a group of tiles drawn together on a single
                            CanvasItem for optimization purposes. This setting defines the length of a square's
                            side in the map's coordinate system. The quadrant size does not apply to a Y sorted
                            TileMapLayer since tiles are grouped by Y position in that case.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
            </section>
            <section ids="physics" names="physics">
                <title>Physics</title>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Collision Enabled</strong> Enables or disables collision.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Use Kinematic Bodies</strong> When true TileMapLayer collision shapes will be instantiated
                            as kinematic bodies.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Collision Visibility Mode</strong> Whether or not the TileMapLayer's collision shapes are
                            visible. If set to default, then it depends on the show collision debug settings.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
            </section>
            <section ids="navigation" names="navigation">
                <title>Navigation</title>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Navigation Enabled</strong> Whether or not navigation regions are enabled.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph><strong>Navigation Visible</strong> Whether or not the TileMapLayer's navigation meshes are
                            visible. If set to default then it depends on the show navigation debug settings.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
                <tip>
                    <paragraph>TileMap built-in navigation has many practical limitations that result in inferior pathfinding performance and pathfollowing quality.</paragraph>
                    <paragraph>After designing the TileMap consider baking it to a more optimized navigation mesh (and disabling the TileMap NavigationLayer) using a <reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_navigationregion2d#class-navigationregion2d"><inline classes="std std-ref">NavigationRegion2D</inline></reference> or the <reference internal="True" refuri="../../classes/class_navigationserver2d#class-navigationserver2d"><inline classes="std std-ref">NavigationServer2D</inline></reference>. See <reference internal="True" refuri="../navigation/navigation_using_navigationmeshes#doc-navigation-using-navigationmeshes"><inline classes="std std-ref">Using navigation meshes</inline></reference> for additional information.</paragraph>
                </tip>
                <warning>
                    <paragraph>2D navigation meshes can not be "layered" or stacked on top of each other like visuals or physic shapes. Attempting to stack navigation meshes on the same navigation map will result in merge and logical errors that break the pathfinding.</paragraph>
                </warning>
            </section>
            <section ids="reordering-layers" names="reordering\ layers">
                <title>Reordering layers</title>
                <paragraph>You can reorder layers by drag-and-dropping their node in the Scene tab. You can
                    also switch between which TileMapLayer node you're working on by using the buttons
                    in the top right corner of the TileMap editor.</paragraph>
                <note>
                    <paragraph>You can create, rename or reorder layers in the future without affecting
                        existing tiles. Be careful though, as <emphasis>removing</emphasis> a layer will also remove
                        all tiles that were placed on the layer.</paragraph>
                </note>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section ids="opening-the-tilemap-editor" names="opening\ the\ tilemap\ editor">
            <title>Opening the TileMap editor</title>
            <paragraph>Select the TileMapLayer node, then open the TileMap panel at the bottom
                of the editor:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id2">
                <image alt="Opening the TileMap panel at the bottom of the editor. The TileMapLayer node must be selected first." candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_open_tilemap_editor.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_open_tilemap_editor.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_open_tilemap_editor.webp"></image>
                <caption>Opening the TileMap panel at the bottom of the editor. The TileMapLayer node must be selected first.</caption>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section ids="selecting-tiles-to-use-for-painting" names="selecting\ tiles\ to\ use\ for\ painting">
            <title>Selecting tiles to use for painting</title>
            <paragraph>First, if you've created additional layers above, make sure you've selected the
                layer you wish to paint on:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id3">
                <image alt="Selecting a layer to paint on in the TileMap editor" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_select_layer.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_select_layer.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_select_layer.webp"></image>
                <caption>Selecting a layer to paint on in the TileMap editor</caption>
            </figure>
            <tip>
                <paragraph>In the 2D editor, the layers you aren't currently editing from the same
                    TileMapLayer node will appear grayed out while in the TileMap editor. You can
                    disable this behavior by clicking the icon next to the layer selection menu
                    (<strong>Highlight Selected TileMap Layer</strong> tooltip).</paragraph>
            </tip>
            <paragraph>You can skip the above step if you haven't created additional layers, as the
                first layer is automatically selected when entering the TileMap editor.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Before you can place tiles in the 2D editor, you must select one or more tiles
                in the TileMap panel located at the bottom of the editor. To do so, click a tile
                in the TileMap panel, or hold down the mouse button to select multiple tiles:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id4">
                <image alt="Selecting a tile in the TileMap editor by clicking it" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_select_single_tile_from_tileset.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_select_single_tile_from_tileset.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_select_single_tile_from_tileset.webp"></image>
                <caption>Selecting a tile in the TileMap editor by clicking it</caption>
            </figure>
            <tip>
                <paragraph>Like in the 2D and TileSet editors, you can pan across the TileMap panel using
                    the middle or right mouse buttons, and zoom using the mouse wheel or buttons in
                    the top-left corner.</paragraph>
            </tip>
            <paragraph>You can also hold down <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal> to append to the current selection. When
                selecting more than one tile, multiple tiles will be placed every time you
                perform a painting operation. This can be used to paint structures composed of
                multiple tiles in a single click (such as large platforms or trees).</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The final selection does not have to be contiguous: if there is empty space
                between selected tiles, it will be left empty in the pattern that will be
                painted in the 2D editor.</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id5">
                <image alt="Selecting multiple tiles in the TileMap editor by holding down the left mouse button" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_select_multiple_tiles_from_tileset.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_select_multiple_tiles_from_tileset.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_select_multiple_tiles_from_tileset.webp"></image>
                <caption>Selecting multiple tiles in the TileMap editor by holding down the left mouse button</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>If you've created alternative tiles in your TileSet, you can select them for
                painting on the right of the base tiles:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id6">
                <image alt="Selecting an alternative tile in the TileMap editor" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_use_alternative_tile.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_use_alternative_tile.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_use_alternative_tile.webp"></image>
                <caption>Selecting an alternative tile in the TileMap editor</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>Lastly, if you've created a <emphasis>scenes collection</emphasis> in the TileSet, you can place scene tiles in the TileMap:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id7">
                <image alt="Placing a scene tile containing particles using the TileMap editor" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_placing_scene_tiles.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_placing_scene_tiles.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_placing_scene_tiles.webp"></image>
                <caption>Placing a scene tile containing particles using the TileMap editor</caption>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section ids="painting-modes-and-tools" names="painting\ modes\ and\ tools">
            <title>Painting modes and tools</title>
            <paragraph>Using the toolbar at the top of the TileMap editor, you can choose between
                several painting modes and tools. These modes affect operation when clicking in
                the 2D editor, <strong>not</strong> the TileMap panel itself.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>From left to right, the painting modes and tools you can choose are:</paragraph>
            <section ids="selection" names="selection">
                <title>Selection</title>
                <paragraph>Select tiles by clicking a single tile, or by holding down the left mouse button to
                    select multiple with a rectangle in the 2D editor. Note that empty space cannot be
                    selected: if you create a rectangle selection, only non-empty tiles will be selected.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>To append to the current selection, hold <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal> then select a tile.
                    To remove from the current selection, hold <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl</literal> then select a tile.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>The selection can then be used in any other painting mode to quickly create copies
                    of an already-placed pattern.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>You can remove the selected tiles from the TileMap by pressing <literal classes="kbd">Del</literal>.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>You can toggle this mode temporarily while in Paint mode by holding <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl</literal>
                    then performing a selection.</paragraph>
                <tip>
                    <paragraph>You can copy and paste tiles that were already placed by performing a
                        selection, pressing <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl + C</literal> then pressing <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl + V</literal>.
                        The selection will be pasted after left-clicking. You can press
                        <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl + V</literal> another time to perform more copies this way.
                        Right-click or press <literal classes="kbd">Escape</literal> to cancel pasting.</paragraph>
                </tip>
            </section>
            <section ids="paint" names="paint">
                <title>Paint</title>
                <paragraph>The standard Paint mode allows you to place tiles by clicking or holding
                    down the left mouse button.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>If you right-click, the currently selected tile will be erased from the tilemap.
                    In other words, it will be replaced by empty space.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>If you have selected multiple tiles in the TileMap or using the Selection tool,
                    they will be placed every time you click or drag the mouse while holding down
                    the left mouse button.</paragraph>
                <tip>
                    <paragraph>While in Paint mode, you can draw a line by holding <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal> <emphasis>before</emphasis>
                        holding down the left mouse button, then dragging the mouse to the line's end
                        point. This is identical to using the Line tool described below.</paragraph>
                    <paragraph>You can also draw a rectangle by holding <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl</literal> and <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal>
                        <emphasis>before</emphasis> holding down the left mouse button, then dragging the mouse to the
                        rectangle's end point. This is identical to using the Rectangle tool
                        described below.</paragraph>
                    <paragraph>Lastly, you can pick existing tiles in the 2D editor by holding <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl</literal>
                        then clicking on a tile (or holding and dragging the mouse).
                        This will switch the currently painted tile(s) to the tile(s) you've just clicked.
                        This is identical to using the Picker tool described below.</paragraph>
                </tip>
            </section>
            <section ids="line" names="line">
                <title>Line</title>
                <paragraph>After selecting Line Paint mode, you can draw in a line that is
                    always 1 tile thick (no matter its orientation).</paragraph>
                <paragraph>If you right-click while in Line Paint mode, you will erase in a line.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>If you have selected multiple tiles in the TileMap or using the Selection tool,
                    you can place them in a repeating pattern across the line.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>You can toggle this mode temporarily while in Paint or Eraser mode by holding
                    <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal> then drawing.</paragraph>
                <figure align="center" ids="id8">
                    <image alt="Using the line tool after selecting two tiles to draw platforms diagonally" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilesets_line_tool_multiple_tiles.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilesets_line_tool_multiple_tiles.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilesets_line_tool_multiple_tiles.webp"></image>
                    <caption>Using the line tool after selecting two tiles to draw platforms diagonally</caption>
                </figure>
            </section>
            <section ids="rectangle" names="rectangle">
                <title>Rectangle</title>
                <paragraph>After selecting Rectangle Paint mode, you can draw in an axis-aligned
                    rectangle.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>If you right-click while in Rectangle Paint mode, you will erase in
                    an axis-aligned rectangle.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>If you have selected multiple tiles in the TileMap or using the Selection tool,
                    you can place them in a repeating pattern within the rectangle.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>You can toggle this mode temporarily while in Paint or Eraser mode by holding
                    <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl</literal> and <literal classes="kbd">Shift</literal> then drawing.</paragraph>
            </section>
            <section ids="bucket-fill" names="bucket\ fill">
                <title>Bucket Fill</title>
                <paragraph>After selecting Bucket Fill mode, you can choose whether painting should be
                    limited to contiguous areas only by toggling the <strong>Contiguous</strong> checkbox that
                    appears on the right of the toolbar.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>If you enable <strong>Contiguous</strong> (the default), only matching tiles that touch the
                    current selection will be replaced. This contiguous check is performed
                    horizontally and vertically, but <emphasis>not</emphasis> diagonally.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>If you disable <strong>Contiguous</strong>, all tiles with the same ID in the entire TileMap will
                    be replaced by the currently selected tile. If selecting an empty tile with
                    <strong>Contiguous</strong> unchecked, all tiles in the rectangle that encompasses the
                    TileMap's effective area will be replaced instead.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>If you right-click while in Bucket Fill mode, you will replace matching tiles
                    with empty tiles.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>If you have selected multiple tiles in the TileMap or using the Selection tool,
                    you can place them in a repeating pattern within the filled area.</paragraph>
                <figure align="center" ids="id9">
                    <image alt="Using the Bucket Fill tool" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_bucket_fill.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_bucket_fill.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_bucket_fill.webp"></image>
                    <caption>Using the Bucket Fill tool</caption>
                </figure>
            </section>
            <section ids="picker" names="picker">
                <title>Picker</title>
                <paragraph>After selecting Picker mode, you can pick existing tiles in the 2D editor by
                    holding <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl</literal> then clicking on a tile. This will switch the currently
                    painted tile to the tile you've just clicked. You can also pick multiple tiles
                    at once by holding down the left mouse button and forming a rectangle selection.
                    Only non-empty tiles can be picked.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>You can toggle this mode temporarily while in Paint mode by holding <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl</literal>
                    then clicking or dragging the mouse.</paragraph>
            </section>
            <section ids="eraser" names="eraser">
                <title>Eraser</title>
                <paragraph>This mode is combined with any other painting mode (Paint, Line, Rectangle,
                    Bucket Fill). When eraser mode is enabled, tiles will be replaced by empty tiles
                    instead of drawing new lines when left-clicking.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>You can toggle this mode temporarily while in any other mode by right-clicking
                    instead of left-clicking.</paragraph>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section ids="painting-randomly-using-scattering" names="painting\ randomly\ using\ scattering">
            <title>Painting randomly using scattering</title>
            <paragraph>While painting, you can optionally enable <emphasis>randomization</emphasis>. When enabled,
                a random tile will be chosen between all the currently selected tiles when
                painting. This is supported with the Paint, Line, Rectangle and Bucket Fill
                tools. For effective paint randomization, you must select multiple tiles
                in the TileMap editor or use scattering (both approaches can be combined).</paragraph>
            <paragraph>If <strong>Scattering</strong> is set to a value greater than 0, there is a chance that no tile
                will be placed when painting. This can be used to add occasional, non-repeating
                detail to large areas (such as adding grass or crumbs on a large top-down
                TileMap).</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Example when using Paint mode:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id10">
                <image alt="Selecting from several times to randomly choose, then painting by holding down the left mouse button" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_scatter_tiles.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_scatter_tiles.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_scatter_tiles.webp"></image>
                <caption>Selecting from several times to randomly choose, then painting by holding down the left mouse button</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>Example when using Bucket Fill mode:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id11">
                <image alt="Using Bucket Fill tool with a single tile, but with randomization and scattering enabled" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_bucket_fill_scatter.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_bucket_fill_scatter.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_bucket_fill_scatter.webp"></image>
                <caption>Using Bucket Fill tool with a single tile, but with randomization and scattering enabled</caption>
            </figure>
            <note>
                <paragraph>Eraser mode does not take randomization and scattering into account.
                    All tiles within the selection are always removed.</paragraph>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section ids="saving-and-loading-premade-tile-placements-using-patterns" names="saving\ and\ loading\ premade\ tile\ placements\ using\ patterns">
            <title>Saving and loading premade tile placements using patterns</title>
            <paragraph>While you can copy and paste tiles while in Select mode, you may wish to save
                premade <emphasis>patterns</emphasis> of tiles to place together in a go. This can be done on a
                per-TileMap basis by choosing the <strong>Patterns</strong> tab of the TileMap editor.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>To create a new pattern, switch to Select mode, perform a selection and press
                <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl + C</literal>. Click on empty space within the Patterns tab (a blue focus
                rectangle should appear around the empty space), then press <literal classes="kbd">Ctrl + V</literal>:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id12">
                <image alt="Creating a new pattern from a selection in the TileMap editor" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_create_pattern.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_create_pattern.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_create_pattern.webp"></image>
                <caption>Creating a new pattern from a selection in the TileMap editor</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>To use an existing pattern, click its image in the <strong>Patterns</strong> tab, switch to
                any painting mode, then left-click somewhere in the 2D editor:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id13">
                <image alt="Placing an existing pattern using the TileMap editor" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_use_pattern.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_use_pattern.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_use_pattern.webp"></image>
                <caption>Placing an existing pattern using the TileMap editor</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>Like multi-tile selections, patterns will be repeated if used with the Line,
                Rectangle or Bucket Fill painting modes.</paragraph>
            <note>
                <paragraph>Despite being edited in the TileMap editor, patterns are stored in the
                    TileSet resource. This allows reusing patterns in different TileMapLayer nodes
                    after loading a TileSet resource saved to an external file.</paragraph>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section ids="handling-tile-connections-automatically-using-terrains" names="handling\ tile\ connections\ automatically\ using\ terrains">
            <title>Handling tile connections automatically using terrains</title>
            <paragraph>To use terrains, the TileMapLayer node must feature at least one terrain set and a
                terrain within this terrain set. See
                <reference internal="True" refuri="using_tilesets#doc-using-tilesets-creating-terrain-sets"><inline classes="std std-ref">Creating terrain sets (autotiling)</inline></reference> if you haven't created a terrain
                set for the TileSet yet.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>There are 3 kinds of painting modes available for terrain connections:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Connect</strong>, where tiles are connected to surrounding tiles on the same
                        TileMapLayer.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Path</strong>, where tiles are connected to tiles painted in the same stroke (until
                        the mouse button is released).</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Tile-specific overrides to resolve conflicts or handle situations not covered
                        by the terrain system.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>The Connect mode is easier to use, but Path is more flexible as it allows for
                more artist control during painting. For instance, Path can allow roads to be
                directly adjacent to each other without being connected to each other, while
                Connect will force both roads to be connected.</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id14">
                <image alt="Selecting Connect mode in the TileMap editor's Terrains tab" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_terrain_select_connect_mode.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_terrain_select_connect_mode.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_terrain_select_connect_mode.webp"></image>
                <caption>Selecting Connect mode in the TileMap editor's Terrains tab</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure align="center" ids="id15">
                <image alt="Selecting Path mode in the TileMap editor's Terrains tab" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_terrain_select_path_mode.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_terrain_select_path_mode.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_terrain_select_path_mode.webp"></image>
                <caption>Selecting Path mode in the TileMap editor's Terrains tab</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>Lastly, you can select specific tiles from the terrain to resolve conflicts in
                certain situations:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id16">
                <image alt="Painting with specific tiles in the TileMap editor's Terrains tab" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_terrain_paint_specific_tiles.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_terrain_paint_specific_tiles.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_terrain_paint_specific_tiles.webp"></image>
                <caption>Painting with specific tiles in the TileMap editor's Terrains tab</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>Any tile that has at least one of its bits set to a value set to the
                corresponding terrain ID will appear in the list of tiles to choose from.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="handling-missing-tiles" names="handling\ missing\ tiles">
            <title>Handling missing tiles</title>
            <paragraph>If you remove tiles in the TileSet that are referenced in a TileMap, the TileMap
                will display a placeholder to indicate that an invalid tile ID is placed:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id17">
                <image alt="Missing tiles in the TileMap editor due to the TileSet reference being broken" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_missing_tiles.webp'}" original_uri="img/using_tilemaps_missing_tiles.webp" uri="tutorials/2d/img/using_tilemaps_missing_tiles.webp"></image>
                <caption>Missing tiles in the TileMap editor due to the TileSet reference being broken</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>These placeholders are <strong>not</strong> visible in the running project, but the tile data
                is still persisted to disk. This allows you to safely close and reopen such
                scenes. Once you re-add a tile with the matching ID, the tiles will appear with
                the new tile's appearance.</paragraph>
            <note>
                <paragraph>Missing tile placeholders may not be visible until you select the TileMapLayer
                    node and open the TileMap editor.</paragraph>
            </note>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
