<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/assets_pipeline/importing_audio_samples.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-importing-audio-samples"></target>
    <section dupnames="importing\ audio\ samples" ids="importing-audio-samples doc-importing-audio-samples" names="doc_importing_audio_samples">
        <title>Importing audio samples</title>
        <section ids="supported-audio-formats" names="supported\ audio\ formats">
            <title>Supported audio formats</title>
            <paragraph>Godot provides 3 options to import your audio data: WAV, Ogg Vorbis and MP3.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Each format has different advantages:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>WAV files use raw data or light compression (IMA ADPCM or Quite OK Audio). Currently
                        they can only be imported in raw format, but Godot allows compression after import.
                        They are lightweight to play back on the CPU (hundreds of simultaneous voices
                        in this format are fine). The downside is that they take up a lot of disk space.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Ogg Vorbis files use a stronger compression that results in much smaller file
                        size, but require significantly more processing power to play back.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>MP3 files use better compression than WAV with IMA ADPCM or Quite OK Audio, but
                        worse than Ogg Vorbis. This means that an MP3 file with roughly equal quality
                        to Ogg Vorbis will be significantly larger. On the bright side, MP3 requires
                        less CPU usage to play back compared to Ogg Vorbis.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <note>
                <paragraph>If you've compiled the Godot editor from source with specific modules disabled,
                    some formats may not be available.</paragraph>
            </note>
            <paragraph>Here is a comparative chart representing the file size of 1 second of audio with
                each format:</paragraph>
            <table>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colwidth="30"></colspec>
                    <colspec colwidth="19"></colspec>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>Format</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>1 second of audio</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>WAV 24-bit, 96 kHz, stereo</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>576 KB</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>WAV 16-bit, 44 kHz, mono</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>88 KB</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>WAV IMA ADPCM, 44 kHz, mono</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>22 KB</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>Quite OK Audio, 44 kHz, mono</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>17 KB</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>MP3 192 Kb/s, stereo</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>24 KB</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>Ogg Vorbis 128 Kb/s, stereo</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>16 KB</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>Ogg Vorbis 96 Kb/s, stereo</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <paragraph>12 KB</paragraph>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <paragraph>Note that the MP3 and Ogg Vorbis figures can vary depending on the encoding
                type. The above figures use <abbreviation explanation="Constant Bit Rate">CBR</abbreviation> encoding for
                simplicity, but most Ogg Vorbis and MP3 files you can find online are encoded
                with <abbreviation explanation="Variable Bit Rate">VBR</abbreviation> encoding which is more efficient.
                VBR encoding makes the effective audio file size depend on how "complex" the
                source audio is.</paragraph>
            <tip>
                <paragraph>Consider using WAV for short and repetitive sound effects, and Ogg Vorbis for
                    music, speech, and long sound effects. MP3 is useful for mobile and web projects
                    where CPU resources are limited, especially when playing multiple compressed
                    sounds at the same time (such as long ambient sounds).</paragraph>
            </tip>
        </section>
        <section dupnames="importing\ audio\ samples" ids="id1">
            <title>Importing audio samples</title>
            <paragraph>Several options are available in the Import dock after selecting a WAV file in
                the FileSystem dock:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id2">
                <image alt="Import options in the Import dock after selecting a WAV file in the FileSystem dock" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/assets_pipeline/img/importing_audio_samples_import_options_wav.webp'}" original_uri="img/importing_audio_samples_import_options_wav.webp" uri="tutorials/assets_pipeline/img/importing_audio_samples_import_options_wav.webp"></image>
                <caption>Import options in the Import dock after selecting a WAV file in the FileSystem dock</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>The set of options available after selecting an Ogg Vorbis or MP3 file is different:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id3">
                <image alt="Import options in the Import dock after selecting an MP3 file in the FileSystem dock" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/assets_pipeline/img/importing_audio_samples_import_options_mp3.webp'}" original_uri="img/importing_audio_samples_import_options_mp3.webp" uri="tutorials/assets_pipeline/img/importing_audio_samples_import_options_mp3.webp"></image>
                <caption>Import options in the Import dock after selecting an MP3 file in the
                    FileSystem dock. Options are identical for Ogg Vorbis files.</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>After importing a sound, you can play it back using the AudioStreamPlayer,
                AudioStreamPlayer2D or AudioStreamPlayer3D nodes. See <reference internal="True" refuri="../audio/audio_streams#doc-audio-streams"><inline classes="std std-ref">Audio streams</inline></reference>
                for more information.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="import-options-wav" names="import\ options\ (wav)">
            <title>Import options (WAV)</title>
        </section>
        <section ids="force-8-bit" names="force\ &gt;\ 8\ bit">
            <title>Force &gt; 8 Bit</title>
            <paragraph>If enabled, forces the imported audio to use 8-bit quantization if the source
                file is 16-bit or higher.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Enabling this is generally not recommended, as 8-bit quantization decreases
                audio quality significantly. If you need smaller file sizes, consider using Ogg
                Vorbis or MP3 audio instead.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="force-mono" names="force\ &gt;\ mono">
            <title>Force &gt; Mono</title>
            <paragraph>If enabled, forces the imported audio to be mono if the source file is stereo.
                This decreases the file size by 50% by merging the two channels into one.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="force-max-rate" names="force\ &gt;\ max\ rate">
            <title>Force &gt; Max Rate</title>
            <paragraph>If set to a value greater than <literal>0</literal>, forces the audio's sample rate to be
                reduced to a value lower than or equal to the value specified here.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>This can decrease file size noticeably on certain sounds, without impacting
                quality depending on the actual sound's contents. See
                <reference internal="True" refid="doc-importing-audio-samples-best-practices"><inline classes="std std-ref">Best practices</inline></reference> for more information.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="edit-trim" names="edit\ &gt;\ trim">
            <title>Edit &gt; Trim</title>
            <paragraph>The source audio file may contain long silences at the beginning and/or the end.
                These silences are inserted by <abbreviation explanation="Digital Audio Workstations">DAWs</abbreviation> when
                saving to a waveform, which increases their size unnecessarily and add latency
                to the moment they are played back.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Enabling <strong>Trim</strong> will automatically trim the beginning and end of the audio if
                it's lower than -50 dB <emphasis>after</emphasis> normalization (see <strong>Edit &gt; Normalize</strong> below).
                A fade-in/fade-out period of 500 samples is also used during trimming to avoid
                audible pops.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="edit-normalize" names="edit\ &gt;\ normalize">
            <title>Edit &gt; Normalize</title>
            <paragraph>If enabled, audio volume will be <emphasis>normalized</emphasis> so that its peak volume is equal
                to 0 dB. When enabled, normalization will make audio sound louder depending on
                its original peak volume.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="edit-loop-mode" names="edit\ &gt;\ loop\ mode">
            <title>Edit &gt; Loop Mode</title>
            <paragraph>Unlike Ogg Vorbis and MP3, WAV files can contain metadata to indicate whether
                they're looping (in addition to loop points). By default, Godot will follow this
                metadata, but you can choose to apply a specific loop mode:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Detect from WAV:</strong> Uses loop information from the WAV metadata.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Disabled:</strong> Don't loop audio, even if metadata indicates the file should be
                        played back looping.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Forward:</strong> Standard audio looping. Plays the audio forward from the beginning
                        to the loop end, then returns to the loop beginning and repeats.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Ping-Pong:</strong> Plays the audio forward until the loop end, then backwards to
                        the loop beginning, repeating this cycle.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Backward:</strong> Plays the audio backwards from the loop end to the loop beginning,
                        then repeats.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>When choosing one of the <strong>Forward</strong>, <strong>Ping-Pong</strong> or <strong>Backward</strong> loop modes,
                loop points can also be defined to make only a specific part of the sound loop.
                <strong>Loop Begin</strong> is set in samples after the beginning of the audio file. <strong>Loop
                    End</strong> is also set in samples after the beginning of the audio file, but will use
                the end of the audio file if set to <literal>-1</literal>.</paragraph>
            <warning>
                <paragraph>In AudioStreamPlayer, the <literal>finished</literal> signal won't be emitted for looping
                    audio when it reaches the end of the audio file, as the audio will keep
                    playing indefinitely.</paragraph>
            </warning>
        </section>
        <section ids="compress-mode" names="compress\ &gt;\ mode">
            <title>Compress &gt; Mode</title>
            <paragraph>Three compression modes can be chosen from for WAV files: <strong>PCM (Uncompressed)</strong>,
                <strong>IMA ADPCM</strong>, or <strong>Quite OK Audio</strong> (default). <strong>IMA ADPCM</strong> reduces file size
                and memory usage a little, at the cost of decreasing quality in an audible manner.
                <strong>Quite OK Audio</strong> reduces file size a bit more than <strong>IMA ADPCM</strong> and the quality
                decrease is much less noticeable, at the cost of slightly higher CPU usage (still
                much lower than MP3).</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Ogg Vorbis and MP3 don't decrease quality as much and can provide greater file
                size reductions, at the cost of higher CPU usage during playback. This higher
                CPU usage is usually not a problem (especially with MP3), unless playing dozens
                of compressed sounds at the same time on mobile/web platforms.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="import-options-ogg-vorbis-and-mp3" names="import\ options\ (ogg\ vorbis\ and\ mp3)">
            <title>Import options (Ogg Vorbis and MP3)</title>
            <section ids="loop" names="loop">
                <title>Loop</title>
                <paragraph>If enabled, the audio will begin playing at the beginning after playback ends by
                    reaching the end of the audio.</paragraph>
                <warning>
                    <paragraph>In AudioStreamPlayer, the <literal>finished</literal> signal won't be emitted for looping
                        audio when it reaches the end of the audio file, as the audio will keep
                        playing indefinitely.</paragraph>
                </warning>
            </section>
            <section ids="loop-offset" names="loop\ offset">
                <title>Loop Offset</title>
                <paragraph>The loop offset determines where audio will start to loop after playback reaches
                    the end of the audio. This can be used to only loop a part of the audio file,
                    which is useful for some ambient sounds or music. The value is determined in
                    seconds relative to the beginning of the audio, so <literal>0</literal> will loop the entire
                    audio file.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>Only has an effect if <strong>Loop</strong> is enabled.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>A more convenient editor for <strong>Loop Offset</strong> is provided in the
                    <reference internal="True" refid="doc-importing-audio-samples-advanced-import-settings"><inline classes="std std-ref">Advanced import settings</inline></reference>
                    dialog, as it lets you preview your changes without having to reimport the audio.</paragraph>
            </section>
            <section ids="bpm" names="bpm">
                <title>BPM</title>
                <paragraph>The Beats Per Minute of the audio track. This should match the BPM measure that
                    was used to compose the track. This is only relevant for music that wishes to
                    make use of interactive music functionality, not sound
                    effects.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>A more convenient editor for <strong>BPM</strong> is provided in the
                    <reference internal="True" refid="doc-importing-audio-samples-advanced-import-settings"><inline classes="std std-ref">Advanced import settings</inline></reference>
                    dialog, as it lets you preview your changes without having to reimport the audio.</paragraph>
            </section>
            <section ids="beat-count" names="beat\ count">
                <title>Beat Count</title>
                <paragraph>The beat count of the audio track. This is only relevant for music that wishes
                    to make use of interactive music functionality, not sound
                    effects.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>A more convenient editor for <strong>Beat Count</strong> is provided in the
                    <reference internal="True" refid="doc-importing-audio-samples-advanced-import-settings"><inline classes="std std-ref">Advanced import settings</inline></reference>
                    dialog, as it lets you preview your changes without having to reimport the audio.</paragraph>
            </section>
            <section ids="bar-beats" names="bar\ beats">
                <title>Bar Beats</title>
                <paragraph>The number of bars within a single beat in the audio track. This is only
                    relevant for music that wishes to make use of interactive music functionality
                    , not sound effects.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>A more convenient editor for <strong>Bar Beats</strong> is provided in the
                    <reference internal="True" refid="doc-importing-audio-samples-advanced-import-settings"><inline classes="std std-ref">Advanced import settings</inline></reference>
                    dialog, as it lets you preview your changes without having to reimport the audio.</paragraph>
                <target refid="doc-importing-audio-samples-advanced-import-settings"></target>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section ids="advanced-import-settings-ogg-vorbis-and-mp3 doc-importing-audio-samples-advanced-import-settings" names="advanced\ import\ settings\ (ogg\ vorbis\ and\ mp3) doc_importing_audio_samples_advanced_import_settings">
            <title>Advanced import settings (Ogg Vorbis and MP3)</title>
            <paragraph>If you double-click an Ogg Vorbis or MP3 file in the FileSystem dock (or choose
                <strong>Advanced…</strong> in the Import dock), you will see a dialog appear:</paragraph>
            <figure align="center" ids="id4">
                <image alt="Advanced dialog when double-clicking an Ogg Vorbis or MP3 file in the FileSystem dock" candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/assets_pipeline/img/importing_audio_samples_advanced_import_settings.webp'}" original_uri="img/importing_audio_samples_advanced_import_settings.webp" uri="tutorials/assets_pipeline/img/importing_audio_samples_advanced_import_settings.webp"></image>
                <caption>Advanced dialog when double-clicking an Ogg Vorbis or MP3 file in the FileSystem dock</caption>
            </figure>
            <paragraph>This dialog allows you to edit the audio's loop point with a real-time preview,
                in addition to the <abbreviation explanation="Beats Per Minute">BPM</abbreviation>, beat count and bar beats.
                These 3 settings are currently unused, but they will be used in the future for
                interactive music support (which allows smoothly transitioning between different
                music tracks).</paragraph>
            <note>
                <paragraph>Unlike WAV files, Ogg Vorbis and MP3 only support a "loop begin" loop point,
                    not a "loop end" point. Looping can also be only be standard forward looping,
                    not ping-pong or backward.</paragraph>
            </note>
            <target refid="doc-importing-audio-samples-best-practices"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="best-practices doc-importing-audio-samples-best-practices" names="best\ practices doc_importing_audio_samples_best_practices">
            <title>Best practices</title>
            <section ids="use-appropriate-quality-settings" names="use\ appropriate\ quality\ settings">
                <title>Use appropriate quality settings</title>
                <paragraph>While keeping pristine-quality audio sources is important if you're performing
                    editing, using the same quality in the exported project is not necessary. For
                    WAV files, Godot offers several import options to reduce the final file size
                    without modifying the source file on disk.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>To reduce memory usage and file size, choose an appropriate quantization,
                    sample rate and number of channels for your audio:</paragraph>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>There's no <emphasis>audible</emphasis> benefit to using 24-bit audio, especially in a game
                            where several sounds are often playing at the same time (which makes it
                            harder to appreciate individual sounds).</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Unless you are slowing down the audio at runtime, there's no <emphasis>audible</emphasis>
                            benefit to using a sample rate greater than 48 kHz. If you wish to keep a
                            source with a higher sample rate for editing, use the <strong>Force &gt; Max Rate</strong>
                            import option to limit the sample rate of the imported sound (only available
                            for WAV files).</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Many sound effects can generally be converted to mono as opposed to stereo.
                            If you wish to keep a source with stereo for editing, use the <strong>Force &gt; Mono</strong>
                            import option to convert the imported sound to mono (only available for WAV files).</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Voices can generally be converted to mono, but can also have their sample rate
                            reduced to 22 kHz without a noticeable loss in quality (unless the voice is
                            very high-pitched). This is because most human voices never go past 11 kHz.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
            </section>
            <section ids="use-real-time-audio-effects-to-reduce-file-size" names="use\ real-time\ audio\ effects\ to\ reduce\ file\ size">
                <title>Use real-time audio effects to reduce file size</title>
                <paragraph>Godot has an <reference internal="True" refuri="../audio/audio_buses#doc-audio-buses"><inline classes="std std-ref">extensive bus system</inline></reference> with built-in effects.
                    This saves SFX artists the need to add reverb to the sound effects,
                    reducing their size greatly and ensuring correct trimming.</paragraph>
                <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/assets_pipeline/img/reverb.png'}" original_uri="img/reverb.png" uri="tutorials/assets_pipeline/img/reverb.png"></image>
                <paragraph>As you can see above, sound effects become much larger in file size with reverb
                    added.</paragraph>
                <seealso>
                    <paragraph>Audio samples can be loaded and saved at runtime using
                        <reference internal="True" refuri="../io/runtime_file_loading_and_saving#doc-runtime-file-loading-and-saving-audio-video-files"><inline classes="std std-ref">runtime file loading and saving</inline></reference>,
                        including from an exported project.</paragraph>
                </seealso>
                <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
