<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/export/exporting_projects.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-exporting-projects"></target>
    <section ids="exporting-projects doc-exporting-projects" names="exporting\ projects doc_exporting_projects">
        <title>Exporting projects</title>
        <section ids="why-export" names="why\ export?">
            <title>Why export?</title>
            <paragraph>Originally, Godot did not have any means to export projects. The
                developers would compile the proper binaries and build the packages for
                each platform manually.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>When more developers (and even non-programmers) started using it, and
                when our company started taking more projects at the same time, it
                became evident that this was a bottleneck.</paragraph>
            <section ids="on-pc" names="on\ pc">
                <title>On PC</title>
                <paragraph>Distributing a game project on PC with Godot is rather easy. Drop
                    the Godot binary in the same directory as the <literal>project.godot</literal> file,
                    then compress the project directory and you are done.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>It sounds simple, but there are probably a few reasons why the developer
                    may not want to do this. The first one is that it may not be desirable
                    to distribute loads of files. Some developers may not like curious users
                    peeking at how the game was made, others may find it inelegant, and so on.
                    Another reason is that the developer might prefer a specially-compiled
                    binary, which is smaller in size, more optimized and does not include
                    tools like the editor and debugger.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>Finally, Godot has a simple but efficient system for
                    <reference internal="True" refuri="exporting_pcks#doc-exporting-pcks"><inline classes="std std-ref">creating DLCs as extra package files</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
            </section>
            <section ids="on-mobile" names="on\ mobile">
                <title>On mobile</title>
                <paragraph>The same scenario on mobile platforms is a little worse.
                    To distribute a project on those devices, a binary for each of
                    those platforms is built, then added to a native project together
                    with the game data.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>This can be troublesome because it means that the developer must be
                    familiarized with the SDK of each platform before even being able to
                    export. While learning each SDK is always encouraged, it can be
                    frustrating to be forced to do it at an undesired time.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>There is also another problem with this approach: different devices
                    prefer some data in different formats to run. The main example of this
                    is texture compression. All PC hardware uses S3TC (BC) compression and
                    that has been standardized for more than a decade, but mobile devices
                    use different formats for texture compression, such as ETC1 and ETC2.</paragraph>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section ids="export-menu" names="export\ menu">
            <title>Export menu</title>
            <paragraph>After many attempts at different export workflows, the current one has
                proven to work the best. At the time of this writing, not all platforms are
                supported yet, but the supported platforms continue to grow.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>To open the export menu, click the <strong>Export</strong> button:</paragraph>
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/export/img/export.webp'}" original_uri="img/export.webp" uri="tutorials/export/img/export.webp"></image>
            <paragraph>The export menu will open. However, it will be completely empty.
                This is because we need to add an export preset.</paragraph>
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/export/img/export_dialog.webp'}" original_uri="img/export_dialog.webp" uri="tutorials/export/img/export_dialog.webp"></image>
            <paragraph>To create an export preset, click the <strong>Add…</strong> button at the top
                of the export menu. This will open a drop-down list of platforms
                to choose from for an export preset.</paragraph>
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/export/img/export_preset.webp'}" original_uri="img/export_preset.webp" uri="tutorials/export/img/export_preset.webp"></image>
            <paragraph>The default options are often enough to export, so tweaking them is
                usually not necessary. However, many platforms require additional
                tools (SDKs) to be installed to be able to export. Additionally, Godot
                needs export templates installed to create packages. The export menu
                will complain when something is missing and will not allow the user to
                export for that platform until they resolve it:</paragraph>
            <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/export/img/export_error.webp'}" original_uri="img/export_error.webp" uri="tutorials/export/img/export_error.webp"></image>
            <paragraph>At that time, the user is expected to come back to the documentation and follow
                instructions on how to properly set up that platform.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The buttons at the bottom of the menu allow you to export the project in a few
                different ways:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Export All: Export the project as a playable build (Godot executable and project data)
                        for all the presets defined. All presets must have an <strong>Export Path</strong> defined for this
                        to work.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Export Project: Export the project as a playable build
                        (Godot executable and project data) for the selected preset.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Export PCK/ZIP: Export the project resources as a PCK or ZIP package.
                        This is not a playable build, it only exports the project data without a Godot executable.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <section ids="export-templates" names="export\ templates">
                <title>Export templates</title>
                <paragraph>Apart from setting up the platform, the export templates must be
                    installed to be able to export projects. They can be obtained as a
                    TPZ file (which is a renamed ZIP archive) from the
                    <reference name="download page of the website" refuri="https://www.godotengine.org/download">download page of the website</reference><target ids="download-page-of-the-website" names="download\ page\ of\ the\ website" refuri="https://www.godotengine.org/download"></target>.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>Once downloaded, they can be installed using the <strong>Install Export Templates</strong>
                    option in the editor:</paragraph>
                <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/export/img/export_templates.webp'}" original_uri="img/export_templates.webp" uri="tutorials/export/img/export_templates.webp"></image>
                <target refid="doc-exporting-projects-export-mode"></target>
            </section>
            <section ids="resource-options doc-exporting-projects-export-mode" names="resource\ options doc_exporting_projects_export_mode">
                <title>Resource options</title>
                <paragraph>When exporting, Godot makes a list of all the files to export and then
                    creates the package. There are 3 different modes for exporting:</paragraph>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Export all resources in the project</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Export selected scenes (and dependencies)</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Export selected resources (and dependencies)</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
                <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/export/img/export_resources.webp'}" original_uri="img/export_resources.webp" uri="tutorials/export/img/export_resources.webp"></image>
                <paragraph><strong>Export all resources in the project</strong> will export every resource in the
                    project. <strong>Export selected scenes</strong> and <strong>Export selected resources</strong> gives
                    you a list of the scenes or resources in the project, and you have to
                    select every scene or resource you want to export.</paragraph>
                <image candidates="{'*': 'tutorials/export/img/export_selected.webp'}" original_uri="img/export_selected.webp" uri="tutorials/export/img/export_selected.webp"></image>
                <paragraph><strong>Export all resources in the project except resources checked below</strong> does
                    exactly what it says, everything will be exported except for what you select
                    in the list.</paragraph>
                <paragraph><strong>Export as dedicated server</strong> will remove all visuals from a project and replace
                    them with a placeholder. This includes Cubemap, CubemapArray, Material, Mesh,
                    Texture2D, Texture2DArray, Texture3D. You can also go into the list of files and
                    specify specific visual resources that you do wish to keep.</paragraph>
                <note>
                    <paragraph>Files and folders whose name begin with a period will never be included in
                        the exported project. This is done to prevent version control folders like
                        <literal>.git</literal> from being included in the exported PCK file.</paragraph>
                </note>
                <paragraph>Below the list of resources are two filters that can be setup. The first allows
                    non-resource files such as <literal>.txt</literal>, <literal>.json</literal> and <literal>.csv</literal> to be exported with
                    the project. The second filter can be used to exclude every file of a certain
                    type without manually deselecting every one. For example, <literal>.png</literal> files.</paragraph>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section ids="configuration-files" names="configuration\ files">
            <title>Configuration files</title>
            <paragraph>The export configuration is stored in two files that can both be found in the project
                directory:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><literal>export_presets.cfg</literal>: This file contains the vast majority of the export
                        configuration and can be safely committed to version control. There is nothing
                        in here that you would normally have to keep secret.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><literal>.godot/export_credentials.cfg</literal>: This file contains export options that are
                        considered confidential, like passwords and encryption keys. It should generally
                        <strong>not</strong> be committed to version control or shared with others unless you know
                        exactly what you are doing.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>Since the credentials file is usually kept out of version control systems, some
                export options will be missing if you clone the project to a new machine. The easiest
                way to deal with this is to copy the file manually from the old location to the new one.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="exporting-from-the-command-line" names="exporting\ from\ the\ command\ line">
            <title>Exporting from the command line</title>
            <paragraph>In production, it is useful to automate builds, and Godot supports this
                with the <literal>--export-release</literal> and <literal>--export-debug</literal> command line parameters.
                Exporting from the command line still requires an export preset to define
                the export parameters. A basic invocation of the command would be:</paragraph>
            <literal_block force="False" highlight_args="{}" language="shell" linenos="False" xml:space="preserve">godot --export-release "Windows Desktop" some_name.exe</literal_block>
            <paragraph>This will export to <literal>some_name.exe</literal>, assuming there is a preset
                called "Windows Desktop" and the template can be found. (The export preset name
                must be written within quotes if it contains spaces or special characters.)
                The output path is <emphasis>relative to the project path</emphasis> or <emphasis>absolute</emphasis>;
                <strong>it does not respect the directory the command was invoked from</strong>.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The output file extension should match the one used by the Godot export process:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Windows: <literal>.exe</literal></paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>macOS: <literal>.app</literal> or <literal>.zip</literal> (or <literal>.dmg</literal> when exporting <emphasis>from</emphasis> macOS)</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Linux: Any extension (including none). <literal>.x86_64</literal> is typically used for 64-bit x86 binaries.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>HTML5: <literal>.zip</literal></paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Android: <literal>.apk</literal></paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>iOS: <literal>.zip</literal></paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>You can also configure it to export <emphasis>only</emphasis> the PCK or ZIP file, allowing
                a single exported main pack file to be used with multiple Godot executables.
                When doing so, the export preset name must still be specified on the command line:</paragraph>
            <literal_block force="False" highlight_args="{}" language="shell" linenos="False" xml:space="preserve">godot --export-pack "Windows Desktop" some_name.pck</literal_block>
            <paragraph>It is often useful to combine the <literal>--export-release</literal> flag with the <literal>--path</literal>
                flag, so that you do not need to <literal>cd</literal> to the project folder before running
                the command:</paragraph>
            <literal_block force="False" highlight_args="{}" language="shell" linenos="False" xml:space="preserve">godot --path /path/to/project --export-release "Windows Desktop" some_name.exe</literal_block>
            <seealso>
                <paragraph>See <reference internal="True" refuri="../editor/command_line_tutorial#doc-command-line-tutorial"><inline classes="std std-ref">Command line tutorial</inline></reference> for more information about using Godot
                    from the command line.</paragraph>
            </seealso>
            <target refid="doc-exporting-projects-pck-versus-zip"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="pck-versus-zip-pack-file-formats doc-exporting-projects-pck-versus-zip" names="pck\ versus\ zip\ pack\ file\ formats doc_exporting_projects_pck_versus_zip">
            <title>PCK versus ZIP pack file formats</title>
            <paragraph>Each format has its upsides and downsides. PCK is the default and recommended
                format for most use cases, but you may want to use a ZIP archive instead
                depending on your needs.</paragraph>
            <paragraph><strong>PCK format:</strong></paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Uncompressed format. Larger file size, but faster to read/write.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Not readable and writable using tools normally present on the user's
                        operating system, even though there are
                        <reference name="third-party tools" refuri="https://github.com/hhyyrylainen/GodotPckTool">third-party tools</reference>
                        to extract and create PCK files.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph><strong>ZIP format:</strong></paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Compressed format. Smaller file size, but slower to read/write.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Readable and writable using tools normally present on the user's operating system.
                        This can be useful to make modding easier (see also <reference internal="True" refuri="exporting_pcks#doc-exporting-pcks"><inline classes="std std-ref">Exporting packs, patches, and mods</inline></reference>).</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <warning>
                <paragraph>Due to a <reference name="known bug" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/42123">known bug</reference>,
                    when using a ZIP file as a pack file, the exported binary will not try to use
                    it automatically. Therefore, you have to create a <emphasis>launcher script</emphasis> that
                    the player can double-click or run from a terminal to launch the project:</paragraph>
                <literal_block force="False" language="none" linenos="False" xml:space="preserve">:: launch.bat (Windows)
@echo off
my_project.exe --main-pack my_project.zip

# launch.sh (Linux)
./my_project.x86_64 --main-pack my_project.zip</literal_block>
                <paragraph>Save the launcher script and place it in the same folder as the exported binary.
                    On Linux, make sure to give executable permissions to the launcher script using
                    the command <literal>chmod +x launch.sh</literal>.</paragraph>
            </warning>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
