<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/best_practices/project_organization.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-project-organization"></target>
    <section ids="project-organization doc-project-organization" names="project\ organization doc_project_organization">
        <title>Project organization</title>
        <section ids="introduction" names="introduction">
            <title>Introduction</title>
            <paragraph>Since Godot has no restrictions on project structure or filesystem usage,
                organizing files when learning the engine can seem challenging. This
                tutorial suggests a workflow which should be a good starting point.
                We will also cover using version control with Godot.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="organization" names="organization">
            <title>Organization</title>
            <paragraph>Godot is scene-based in nature, and uses the filesystem as-is,
                without metadata or an asset database.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Unlike other engines, many resources are contained within the scene
                itself, so the amount of files in the filesystem is considerably lower.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Considering that, the most common approach is to group assets as close
                to scenes as possible; when a project grows, it makes it more
                maintainable.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>As an example, one can usually place into a single folder their basic assets,
                such as sprite images, 3D model meshes, materials, and music, etc.
                They can then use a separate folder to store built levels that use them.</paragraph>
            <literal_block force="False" highlight_args="{}" language="none" linenos="False" xml:space="preserve">/project.godot
/docs/.gdignore  # See "Ignoring specific folders" below
/docs/learning.html
/models/town/house/house.dae
/models/town/house/window.png
/models/town/house/door.png
/characters/player/cubio.dae
/characters/player/cubio.png
/characters/enemies/goblin/goblin.dae
/characters/enemies/goblin/goblin.png
/characters/npcs/suzanne/suzanne.dae
/characters/npcs/suzanne/suzanne.png
/levels/riverdale/riverdale.scn</literal_block>
        </section>
        <section ids="style-guide" names="style\ guide">
            <title>Style guide</title>
            <paragraph>For consistency across projects, we recommend following these guidelines:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Use <strong>snake_case</strong> for folder and file names (with the exception of C#
                        scripts). This sidesteps case sensitivity issues that can crop up after
                        exporting a project on Windows. C# scripts are an exception to this rule,
                        as the convention is to name them after the class name which should be
                        in PascalCase.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Use <strong>PascalCase</strong> for node names, as this matches built-in node casing.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>In general, keep third-party resources in a top-level <literal>addons/</literal> folder, even
                        if they aren't editor plugins. This makes it easier to track which files are
                        third-party. There are some exceptions to this rule; for instance, if you use
                        third-party game assets for a character, it makes more sense to include them
                        within the same folder as the character scenes and scripts.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
        </section>
        <section ids="importing" names="importing">
            <title>Importing</title>
            <paragraph>Godot versions prior to 3.0 did the import process from files outside
                the project. While this can be useful in large projects, it
                resulted in an organization hassle for most developers.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Because of this, assets are now transparently imported from within the project
                folder.</paragraph>
            <section ids="ignoring-specific-folders" names="ignoring\ specific\ folders">
                <title>Ignoring specific folders</title>
                <paragraph>To prevent Godot from importing files contained in a specific folder, create
                    an empty file called <literal>.gdignore</literal> in the folder (the leading <literal>.</literal> is required).
                    This can be useful to speed up the initial project importing.</paragraph>
                <note>
                    <paragraph>To create a file whose name starts with a dot on Windows, place a dot
                        at both the beginning and end of the filename (".gdignore."). Windows
                        will automatically remove the trailing dot when you confirm the name.</paragraph>
                    <paragraph>Alternatively, you can use a text editor such as Notepad++ or use the
                        following command in a command prompt: <literal>type nul &gt; .gdignore</literal></paragraph>
                </note>
                <paragraph>Once the folder is ignored, resources in that folder can't be loaded anymore
                    using the <literal>load()</literal> and <literal>preload()</literal> methods. Ignoring a folder will also
                    automatically hide it from the FileSystem dock, which can be useful to reduce clutter.</paragraph>
                <paragraph>Note that the <literal>.gdignore</literal> file's contents are ignored, which is why the file
                    should be empty. It does not support patterns like <literal>.gitignore</literal> files do.</paragraph>
                <target refid="doc-project-organization-case-sensitivity"></target>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section ids="case-sensitivity doc-project-organization-case-sensitivity" names="case\ sensitivity doc_project_organization_case_sensitivity">
            <title>Case sensitivity</title>
            <paragraph>Windows and recent macOS versions use case-insensitive filesystems by default,
                whereas Linux distributions use a case-sensitive filesystem by default.
                This can cause issues after exporting a project, since Godot's PCK virtual
                filesystem is case-sensitive. To avoid this, it's recommended to stick to
                <literal>snake_case</literal> naming for all files in the project (and lowercase characters
                in general).</paragraph>
            <note>
                <paragraph>You can break this rule when style guides say otherwise (such as the
                    C# style guide). Still, be consistent to avoid mistakes.</paragraph>
            </note>
            <paragraph>On Windows 10, to further avoid mistakes related to case sensitivity,
                you can also make the project folder case-sensitive. After enabling the Windows
                Subsystem for Linux feature, run the following command in a PowerShell window:</paragraph>
            <literal_block force="False" language="gdscript" linenos="False" xml:space="preserve"># To enable case-sensitivity:
fsutil file setcasesensitiveinfo &lt;path to project folder&gt; enable

# To disable case-sensitivity:
fsutil file setcasesensitiveinfo &lt;path to project folder&gt; disable</literal_block>
            <paragraph>If you haven't enabled the Windows Subsystem for Linux, you can enter the
                following line in a PowerShell window <emphasis>running as Administrator</emphasis> then reboot
                when asked:</paragraph>
            <literal_block force="False" language="gdscript" linenos="False" xml:space="preserve">Enable-WindowsOptionalFeature -Online -FeatureName Microsoft-Windows-Subsystem-Linux</literal_block>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
