<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/tutorials/scripting/filesystem.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-filesystem"></target>
    <section ids="file-system doc-filesystem" names="file\ system doc_filesystem">
        <title>File system</title>
        <section ids="introduction" names="introduction">
            <title>Introduction</title>
            <paragraph>A file system manages how assets are stored and how they are accessed.
                A well-designed file system also allows multiple developers to edit the
                same source files and assets while collaborating. Godot stores
                all assets as files in its file system.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="implementation" names="implementation">
            <title>Implementation</title>
            <paragraph>The file system stores resources on disk. Anything, from a script, to a scene or a
                PNG image is a resource to the engine. If a resource contains properties
                that reference other resources on disk, the paths to those resources are also
                included. If a resource has sub-resources that are built-in, the resource is
                saved in a single file together with all the bundled sub-resources. For
                example, a font resource is often bundled together with the font textures.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The Godot file system avoids using metadata files. Existing asset managers and VCSs
                are better than anything we can implement, so Godot tries its best to play along
                with Subversion, Git, Mercurial, etc.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Example of file system contents:</paragraph>
            <literal_block force="False" highlight_args="{}" language="none" linenos="False" xml:space="preserve">/project.godot
/enemy/enemy.tscn
/enemy/enemy.gd
/enemy/enemysprite.png
/player/player.gd</literal_block>
        </section>
        <section ids="project-godot" names="project.godot">
            <title>project.godot</title>
            <paragraph>The <literal>project.godot</literal> file is the project description file, and it is always found
                at the root of the project. In fact, its location defines where the root is. This
                is the first file that Godot looks for when opening a project.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>This file contains the project configuration in plain text, using the win.ini
                format. Even an empty <literal>project.godot</literal> can function as a basic definition of
                a blank project.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="path-delimiter" names="path\ delimiter">
            <title>Path delimiter</title>
            <paragraph>Godot only supports <literal>/</literal> as a path delimiter. This is done for
                portability reasons. All operating systems support this, even Windows,
                so a path such as <literal>C:\project\project.godot</literal> needs to be typed as
                <literal>C:/project/project.godot</literal>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="resource-path" names="resource\ path">
            <title>Resource path</title>
            <paragraph>When accessing resources, using the host OS file system layout can be
                cumbersome and non-portable. To solve this problem, the special path
                <literal>res://</literal> was created.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The path <literal>res://</literal> will always point at the project root (where
                <literal>project.godot</literal> is located, so <literal>res://project.godot</literal> is always
                valid).</paragraph>
            <paragraph>This file system is read-write only when running the project locally from
                the editor. When exported or when running on different devices (such as
                phones or consoles, or running from DVD), the file system will become
                read-only and writing will no longer be permitted.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="user-path" names="user\ path">
            <title>User path</title>
            <paragraph>Writing to disk is still needed for tasks such as saving game state or
                downloading content packs. To this end, the engine ensures that there is a
                special path <literal>user://</literal> that is always writable. This path resolves
                differently depending on the OS the project is running on. Local path
                resolution is further explained in <reference internal="True" refuri="../io/data_paths#doc-data-paths"><inline classes="std std-ref">File paths in Godot projects</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="host-file-system" names="host\ file\ system">
            <title>Host file system</title>
            <paragraph>Alternatively host file system paths can also be used, but this is not recommended
                for a released product as these paths are not guaranteed to work on all platforms.
                However, using host file system paths can be useful when writing development
                tools in Godot.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="drawbacks" names="drawbacks">
            <title>Drawbacks</title>
            <paragraph>There are some drawbacks to this file system design. The first issue is that
                moving assets around (renaming them or moving them from one path to another inside
                the project) will break existing references to these assets. These references will
                have to be re-defined to point at the new asset location.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>To avoid this, do all your move, delete and rename operations from within Godot, on
                the FileSystem dock. Never move assets from outside Godot, or dependencies will have
                to be fixed manually (Godot detects this and helps you fix them anyway, but why
                go the hard route?).</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The second is that, under Windows and macOS, file and path names are case insensitive.
                If a developer working in a case insensitive host file system saves an asset as <literal>myfile.PNG</literal>,
                but then references it as <literal>myfile.png</literal>, it will work fine on their platform, but not
                on other platforms, such as Linux, Android, etc. This may also apply to exported binaries,
                which use a compressed package to store all files.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>It is recommended that your team clearly define a naming convention for files when
                working with Godot. One fool-proof convention is to only allow lowercase
                file and path names.</paragraph>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
