<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/about/faq.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <meta content="FAQ" name="keywords"></meta>
    <target refid="doc-faq"></target>
    <section ids="frequently-asked-questions doc-faq" names="frequently\ asked\ questions doc_faq">
        <title>Frequently asked questions</title>
        <section ids="what-can-i-do-with-godot-how-much-does-it-cost-what-are-the-license-terms" names="what\ can\ i\ do\ with\ godot?\ how\ much\ does\ it\ cost?\ what\ are\ the\ license\ terms?">
            <title>What can I do with Godot? How much does it cost? What are the license terms?</title>
            <paragraph>Godot is <reference name="Free and open source Software" refuri="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open_source_software">Free and open source Software</reference><target ids="free-and-open-source-software" names="free\ and\ open\ source\ software" refuri="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open_source_software"></target>
                available under the <reference name="OSI-approved" refuri="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT">OSI-approved</reference><target ids="osi-approved" names="osi-approved" refuri="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT"></target> MIT license. This means it is
                free as in "free speech" as well as in "free beer."</paragraph>
            <paragraph>In short:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="*">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>You are free to download and use Godot for any purpose: personal, non-profit, commercial, or otherwise.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>You are free to modify, distribute, redistribute, and remix Godot to your heart's content, for any reason,
                        both non-commercially and commercially.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>All the contents of this accompanying documentation are published under the permissive Creative Commons
                Attribution 3.0 (<reference name="CC BY 3.0" refuri="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">CC BY 3.0</reference><target ids="cc-by-3-0" names="cc\ by\ 3.0" refuri="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/"></target>) license, with attribution
                to "Juan Linietsky, Ariel Manzur and the Godot Engine community."</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Logos and icons are generally under the same Creative Commons license. Note
                that some third-party libraries included with Godot's source code may have
                different licenses.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>For full details, look at the <reference name="COPYRIGHT.txt" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/COPYRIGHT.txt">COPYRIGHT.txt</reference><target ids="copyright-txt" names="copyright.txt" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/COPYRIGHT.txt"></target>
                as well as the <reference name="LICENSE.txt" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/LICENSE.txt">LICENSE.txt</reference><target ids="license-txt" names="license.txt" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/LICENSE.txt"></target>
                and <reference name="LOGO_LICENSE.txt" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/LOGO_LICENSE.txt">LOGO_LICENSE.txt</reference><target ids="logo-license-txt" names="logo_license.txt" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/LOGO_LICENSE.txt"></target> files
                in the Godot repository.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Also, see <reference name="the license page on the Godot website" refuri="https://godotengine.org/license">the license page on the Godot website</reference><target ids="the-license-page-on-the-godot-website" names="the\ license\ page\ on\ the\ godot\ website" refuri="https://godotengine.org/license"></target>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="which-platforms-are-supported-by-godot" names="which\ platforms\ are\ supported\ by\ godot?">
            <title>Which platforms are supported by Godot?</title>
            <paragraph><strong>For the editor:</strong></paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="*">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Windows</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>macOS</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Linux, *BSD</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Android (experimental)</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><reference name="Web" refuri="https://editor.godotengine.org/">Web</reference> (experimental)</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph><strong>For exporting your games:</strong></paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="*">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Windows</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>macOS</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Linux, *BSD</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Android</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>iOS</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Web</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>Both 32- and 64-bit binaries are supported where it makes sense, with 64
                being the default. Official macOS builds support Apple Silicon natively as well as x86_64.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Some users also report building and using Godot successfully on ARM-based
                systems with Linux, like the Raspberry Pi.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The Godot team can't provide an open source console export due to the licensing
                terms imposed by console manufacturers. Regardless of the engine you use,
                though, releasing games on consoles is always a lot of work. You can read more
                about <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/platform/consoles#doc-consoles"><inline classes="std std-ref">Console support in Godot</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>For more on this, see the sections on <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/export/index#toc-learn-workflow-export"><inline classes="std std-ref">exporting</inline></reference>
                and <reference internal="True" refuri="../engine_details/development/compiling/index#toc-devel-compiling"><inline classes="std std-ref">compiling Godot yourself</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
            <note>
                <paragraph>Godot 3 also had support for Universal Windows Platform (UWP). This platform
                    port was removed in Godot 4 due to lack of maintenance, and it being
                    deprecated by Microsoft. It is still available in the current stable release
                    of Godot 3 for interested users.</paragraph>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section ids="which-programming-languages-are-supported-in-godot" names="which\ programming\ languages\ are\ supported\ in\ godot?">
            <title>Which programming languages are supported in Godot?</title>
            <paragraph>The officially supported languages for Godot are GDScript, C#, and C++.
                See the subcategories for each language in the <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/scripting/index#toc-learn-scripting"><inline classes="std std-ref">scripting</inline></reference> section.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>If you are just starting out with either Godot or game development in general,
                GDScript is the recommended language to learn and use since it is native to Godot.
                While scripting languages tend to be less performant than lower-level languages in
                the long run, for prototyping, developing Minimum Viable Products (MVPs), and
                focusing on Time-To-Market (TTM), GDScript will provide a fast, friendly, and capable
                way of developing your games.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Note that C# support is still relatively new, and as such, you may encounter
                some issues along the way. C# support is also currently missing on the web
                platform. Our friendly and hard-working development community is always
                ready to tackle new problems as they arise, but since this is an open source
                project, we recommend that you first do some due diligence yourself. Searching
                through discussions on
                <reference name="open issues" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Aopen+is%3Aissue+label%3Atopic%3Adotnet">open issues</reference>
                is a great way to start your troubleshooting.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>As for new languages, support is possible via third parties with GDExtensions. (See the question
                about plugins below). Work is currently underway, for example, on unofficial bindings for Godot
                to <reference name="Python" refuri="https://github.com/touilleMan/godot-python">Python</reference><target ids="python" names="python" refuri="https://github.com/touilleMan/godot-python"></target> and <reference name="Nim" refuri="https://github.com/pragmagic/godot-nim">Nim</reference><target ids="nim" names="nim" refuri="https://github.com/pragmagic/godot-nim"></target>.</paragraph>
            <target refid="doc-faq-what-is-gdscript"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="what-is-gdscript-and-why-should-i-use-it doc-faq-what-is-gdscript" names="what\ is\ gdscript\ and\ why\ should\ i\ use\ it? doc_faq_what_is_gdscript">
            <title>What is GDScript and why should I use it?</title>
            <paragraph>GDScript is Godot's integrated scripting language. It was built from the ground
                up to maximize Godot's potential in the least amount of code, affording both novice
                and expert developers alike to capitalize on Godot's strengths as fast as possible.
                If you've ever written anything in a language like Python before, then you'll feel
                right at home. For examples and a complete overview of the power GDScript offers
                you, check out the <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/scripting/gdscript/index#doc-gdscript"><inline classes="std std-ref">GDScript scripting guide</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>There are several reasons to use GDScript, but the most salient reason is the overall
                <strong>reduction of complexity</strong>.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The original intent of creating a tightly integrated, custom scripting language for
                Godot was two-fold: first, it reduces the amount of time necessary to get up and running
                with Godot, giving developers a rapid way of exposing themselves to the engine with a
                focus on productivity; second, it reduces the overall burden of maintenance, attenuates
                the dimensionality of issues, and allows the developers of the engine to focus on squashing
                bugs and improving features related to the engine core, rather than spending a lot of time
                trying to get a small set of incremental features working across a large set of languages.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Since Godot is an open source project, it was imperative from the start to prioritize a
                more integrated and seamless experience over attracting additional users by supporting
                more familiar programming languages, especially when supporting those more familiar
                languages would result in a worse experience. We understand if you would rather use
                another language in Godot (see the list of supported options above). That being said, if
                you haven't given GDScript a try, try it for <strong>three days</strong>. Just like Godot,
                once you see how powerful it is and how rapid your development becomes, we think GDScript
                will grow on you.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>More information about getting comfortable with GDScript or dynamically typed
                languages can be found in the <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/scripting/gdscript/gdscript_advanced#doc-gdscript-more-efficiently"><inline classes="std std-ref">GDScript: An introduction to dynamic languages</inline></reference> tutorial.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="what-were-the-motivations-behind-creating-gdscript" names="what\ were\ the\ motivations\ behind\ creating\ gdscript?">
            <title>What were the motivations behind creating GDScript?</title>
            <paragraph>In the early days, the engine used the <reference name="Lua" refuri="https://www.lua.org">Lua</reference> scripting
                language. Lua can be fast thanks to LuaJIT, but creating bindings to an object-oriented
                system (by using fallbacks) was complex and slow and took an enormous
                amount of code. After some experiments with <reference name="Python" refuri="https://www.python.org">Python</reference>,
                that also proved difficult to embed.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The main reasons for creating a custom scripting language for Godot were:</paragraph>
            <enumerated_list enumtype="arabic" prefix="" suffix=".">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Poor threading support in most script VMs, and Godot uses threads
                        (Lua, Python, Squirrel, JavaScript, ActionScript, etc.).</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Poor class-extending support in most script VMs, and adapting to
                        the way Godot works is highly inefficient (Lua, Python, JavaScript).</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Many existing languages have horrible interfaces for binding to C++, resulting in a
                        large amount of code, bugs, bottlenecks, and general inefficiency (Lua, Python,
                        Squirrel, JavaScript, etc.). We wanted to focus on a great engine, not a great number
                        of integrations.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>No native vector types (Vector3, Transform3D, etc.), resulting in highly
                        reduced performance when using custom types (Lua, Python, Squirrel,
                        JavaScript, ActionScript, etc.).</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Garbage collector results in stalls or unnecessarily large memory
                        usage (Lua, Python, JavaScript, ActionScript, etc.).</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Difficulty integrating with the code editor for providing code
                        completion, live editing, etc. (all of them).</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </enumerated_list>
            <paragraph>GDScript was designed to curtail the issues above, and more.</paragraph>
            <target refid="doc-faq-which-programming-language-is-fastest"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="which-programming-language-is-fastest doc-faq-which-programming-language-is-fastest" names="which\ programming\ language\ is\ fastest? doc_faq_which_programming_language_is_fastest">
            <title>Which programming language is fastest?</title>
            <paragraph>In most games, the <emphasis>scripting language</emphasis> itself is not the cause of performance
                problems. Instead, performance is slowed by inefficient algorithms (which are
                slow in all languages), by GPU performance, or by the common C++ engine code
                like physics or navigation. All languages supported by Godot are fast enough for
                general-purpose scripting. You should choose a language based on other factors,
                like ease-of-use, familiarity, platform support, or language features.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>In general, the performance of C# and GDScript is within the same order of
                magnitude, and C++ is faster than both.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Comparing GDScript performance to C# is tricky, since C# can be faster in some
                specific cases. The C# <emphasis>language</emphasis> itself tends to be faster than GDScript, which
                means that C# can be faster in situations with few calls to Godot engine code.
                However, C# can be slower than GDScript when making many Godot API calls, due
                to the cost of <emphasis>marshalling</emphasis>. C#'s performance can also be brought down by garbage
                collection which occurs at random and unpredictable moments. This can result in
                stuttering issues in complex projects, and is not exclusive to Godot.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>C++, using <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/scripting/gdextension/what_is_gdextension#doc-what-is-gdextension"><inline classes="std std-ref">GDExtension</inline></reference>, will almost always be
                faster than either C# or GDScript. However, C++ is less easy to use than C# or
                GDScript, and is slower to develop with.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>You can also use multiple languages within a single project, with
                <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/scripting/cross_language_scripting#doc-cross-language-scripting"><inline classes="std std-ref">cross-language scripting</inline></reference>, or by using
                GDExtension and scripting languages together. Be aware that doing so comes with
                its own complications.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="what-3d-model-formats-does-godot-support" names="what\ 3d\ model\ formats\ does\ godot\ support?">
            <title>What 3D model formats does Godot support?</title>
            <paragraph>You can find detailed information on supported formats, how to export them from
                your 3D modeling software, and how to import them for Godot in the
                <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/assets_pipeline/importing_3d_scenes/index#doc-importing-3d-scenes"><inline classes="std std-ref">Importing 3D scenes</inline></reference> documentation.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="will-insert-closed-sdk-such-as-fmod-gameworks-etc-be-supported-in-godot" names="will\ [insert\ closed\ sdk\ such\ as\ fmod,\ gameworks,\ etc.]\ be\ supported\ in\ godot?">
            <title>Will [insert closed SDK such as FMOD, GameWorks, etc.] be supported in Godot?</title>
            <paragraph>The aim of Godot is to create a free and open source MIT-licensed engine that
                is modular and extendable. There are no plans for the core engine development
                community to support any third-party, closed-source/proprietary SDKs, as integrating
                with these would go against Godot's ethos.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>That said, because Godot is open source and modular, nothing prevents you or
                anyone else interested in adding those libraries as a module and shipping your
                game with them, as either open- or closed-source.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>To see how support for your SDK of choice could still be provided, look at the
                Plugins question below.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>If you know of a third-party SDK that is not supported by Godot but that offers
                free and open source integration, consider starting the integration work yourself.
                Godot is not owned by one person; it belongs to the community, and it grows along
                with ambitious community contributors like you.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="how-can-i-extend-godot" names="how\ can\ i\ extend\ godot?">
            <title>How can I extend Godot?</title>
            <paragraph>For extending Godot, like creating Godot Editor plugins or adding support
                for additional languages, take a look at <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/plugins/editor/making_plugins#doc-making-plugins"><inline classes="std std-ref">EditorPlugins</inline></reference>
                and tool scripts.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Also, see the official blog post on GDExtension, a way to develop native extensions for Godot:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="*">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><reference name="Introducing GDNative's successor, GDExtension" refuri="https://godotengine.org/article/introducing-gd-extensions">Introducing GDNative's successor, GDExtension</reference><target ids="introducing-gdnative-s-successor-gdextension" names="introducing\ gdnative's\ successor,\ gdextension" refuri="https://godotengine.org/article/introducing-gd-extensions"></target></paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>You can also take a look at the GDScript implementation, the Godot modules,
                as well as the <reference name="Jolt physics engine integration" refuri="https://github.com/godot-jolt/godot-jolt">Jolt physics engine integration</reference>
                for Godot. This would be a good starting point to see how another
                third-party library integrates with Godot.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="how-do-i-install-the-godot-editor-on-my-system-for-desktop-integration" names="how\ do\ i\ install\ the\ godot\ editor\ on\ my\ system\ (for\ desktop\ integration)?">
            <title>How do I install the Godot editor on my system (for desktop integration)?</title>
            <paragraph>Since you don't need to actually install Godot on your system to run it,
                this means desktop integration is not performed automatically.
                There are two ways to overcome this. You can install Godot from
                <reference name="Steam" refuri="https://store.steampowered.com/app/404790/Godot_Engine/">Steam</reference> (all platforms),
                <reference name="Scoop" refuri="https://scoop.sh/">Scoop</reference> (Windows), <reference name="Homebrew" refuri="https://brew.sh/">Homebrew</reference> (macOS)
                or <reference name="Flathub" refuri="https://flathub.org/apps/details/org.godotengine.Godot">Flathub</reference> (Linux).
                This will automatically perform the required steps for desktop integration.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Alternatively, you can manually perform the steps that an installer would do for you:</paragraph>
            <section ids="windows" names="windows">
                <title>Windows</title>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Move the Godot executable to a stable location (i.e. outside of your Downloads folder),
                            so you don't accidentally move it and break the shortcut in the future.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Right-click the Godot executable and choose <strong>Create Shortcut</strong>.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Move the created shortcut to <literal>%APPDATA%\Microsoft\Windows\Start Menu\Programs</literal>.
                            This is the user-wide location for shortcuts that will appear in the Start menu.
                            You can also pin Godot in the task bar by right-clicking the executable and choosing
                            <strong>Pin to Task Bar</strong>.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
            </section>
            <section ids="macos" names="macos">
                <title>macOS</title>
                <paragraph>Drag the extracted Godot application to <literal>/Applications/Godot.app</literal>, then drag it
                    to the Dock if desired. Spotlight will be able to find Godot as long as it's in
                    <literal>/Applications</literal> or <literal>~/Applications</literal>.</paragraph>
            </section>
            <section ids="linux" names="linux">
                <title>Linux</title>
                <bullet_list bullet="-">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Move the Godot binary to a stable location (i.e. outside of your Downloads folder),
                            so you don't accidentally move it and break the shortcut in the future.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Rename and move the Godot binary to a location present in your <literal>PATH</literal> environment variable.
                            This is typically <literal>/usr/local/bin/godot</literal> or <literal>/usr/bin/godot</literal>.
                            Doing this requires administrator privileges,
                            but this also allows you to
                            <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/editor/command_line_tutorial#doc-command-line-tutorial"><inline classes="std std-ref">run the Godot editor from a terminal</inline></reference> by entering <literal>godot</literal>.</paragraph>
                        <bullet_list bullet="-">
                            <list_item>
                                <paragraph>If you cannot move the Godot editor binary to a protected location, you can
                                    keep the binary somewhere in your home directory, and modify the <literal>Path=</literal>
                                    line in the <literal>.desktop</literal> file linked below to contain the full <emphasis>absolute</emphasis> path
                                    to the Godot binary.</paragraph>
                            </list_item>
                        </bullet_list>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Save <reference name="this .desktop file" refuri="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/misc/dist/linux/org.godotengine.Godot.desktop">this .desktop file</reference>
                            to <literal>$HOME/.local/share/applications/</literal>. If you have administrator privileges,
                            you can also save the <literal>.desktop</literal> file to <literal>/usr/local/share/applications</literal>
                            to make the shortcut available for all users.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section ids="is-the-godot-editor-a-portable-application" names="is\ the\ godot\ editor\ a\ portable\ application?">
            <title>Is the Godot editor a portable application?</title>
            <paragraph>In its default configuration, Godot is <emphasis>semi-portable</emphasis>. Its executable can run
                from any location (including non-writable locations) and never requires
                administrator privileges.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>However, configuration files will be written to the user-wide configuration or
                data directory. This is usually a good approach, but this means configuration files
                will not carry across machines if you copy the folder containing the Godot executable.
                See <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/io/data_paths#doc-data-paths"><inline classes="std std-ref">File paths in Godot projects</inline></reference> for more information.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>If <emphasis>true</emphasis> portable operation is desired (e.g. for use on a USB stick),
                follow the steps in <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/io/data_paths#doc-data-paths-self-contained-mode"><inline classes="std std-ref">Self-contained mode</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="why-does-godot-aim-to-keep-its-core-feature-set-small" names="why\ does\ godot\ aim\ to\ keep\ its\ core\ feature\ set\ small?">
            <title>Why does Godot aim to keep its core feature set small?</title>
            <paragraph>Godot intentionally does not include features that can be implemented by add-ons
                unless they are used very often. One example of something not used often is
                advanced artificial intelligence functionality.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>There are several reasons for this:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Code maintenance and surface for bugs.</strong> Every time we accept new code in
                        the Godot repository, existing contributors often take the responsibility of
                        maintaining it. Some contributors don't always stick around after getting
                        their code merged, which can make it difficult for us to maintain the code in
                        question. This can lead to poorly maintained features with bugs that are never
                        fixed. On top of that, the "API surface" that needs to be tested and checked
                        for regressions keeps increasing over time.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Ease of contribution.</strong> By keeping the codebase small and tidy, it can remain
                        fast and easy to compile from source. This makes it easier for new
                        contributors to get started with Godot, without requiring them to purchase
                        high-end hardware.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Keeping the binary size small for the editor.</strong> Not everyone has a fast Internet
                        connection. Ensuring that everyone can download the Godot editor, extract it
                        and run it in less than 5 minutes makes Godot more accessible to developers in
                        all countries.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph><strong>Keeping the binary size small for export templates.</strong> This directly impacts the
                        size of projects exported with Godot. On mobile and web platforms, keeping
                        file sizes low is important to ensure fast installation and loading on
                        underpowered devices. Again, there are many countries where high-speed
                        Internet is not readily available. To add to this, strict data usage caps are
                        often in effect in those countries.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>For all the reasons above, we have to be selective of what we can accept as core
                functionality in Godot. This is why we are aiming to move some core
                functionality to officially supported add-ons in future versions of Godot.
                In terms of binary size, this also has the advantage of making you pay only for
                what you actually use in your project. (In the meantime, you can
                <reference internal="True" refuri="../engine_details/development/compiling/optimizing_for_size#doc-optimizing-for-size"><inline classes="std std-ref">compile custom export templates with unused features disabled</inline></reference>
                to optimize the distribution size of your project.)</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="how-should-assets-be-created-to-handle-multiple-resolutions-and-aspect-ratios" names="how\ should\ assets\ be\ created\ to\ handle\ multiple\ resolutions\ and\ aspect\ ratios?">
            <title>How should assets be created to handle multiple resolutions and aspect ratios?</title>
            <paragraph>This question pops up often and it's probably thanks to the misunderstanding
                created by Apple when they originally doubled the resolution of their devices.
                It made people think that having the same assets in different resolutions was a
                good idea, so many continued towards that path. That originally worked to a
                point and only for Apple devices, but then several Android and Apple devices
                with different resolutions and aspect ratios were created, with a very wide
                range of sizes and DPIs.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The most common and proper way to achieve this is to, instead, use a single base
                resolution for the game and only handle different screen aspect ratios. This is
                mostly needed for 2D, as in 3D, it's just a matter of camera vertical or
                horizontal FOV.</paragraph>
            <enumerated_list enumtype="arabic" prefix="" suffix=".">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Choose a single base resolution for your game. Even if there are
                        devices that go up to 1440p and devices that go down to 400p, regular
                        hardware scaling in your device will take care of this at little or
                        no performance cost. The most common choices are either near 1080p
                        (1920x1080) or 720p (1280x720). Keep in mind the higher the
                        resolution, the larger your assets, the more memory they will take
                        and the longer the time it will take for loading.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Use the stretch options in Godot; canvas items stretching while keeping
                        aspect ratios works best. Check the <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/rendering/multiple_resolutions#doc-multiple-resolutions"><inline classes="std std-ref">Multiple resolutions</inline></reference> tutorial
                        on how to achieve this.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Determine a minimum resolution and then decide if you want your game
                        to stretch vertically or horizontally for different aspect ratios, or
                        if there is one aspect ratio and you want black bars to appear
                        instead. This is also explained in <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/rendering/multiple_resolutions#doc-multiple-resolutions"><inline classes="std std-ref">Multiple resolutions</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>For user interfaces, use the <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/ui/size_and_anchors#doc-size-and-anchors"><inline classes="std std-ref">anchoring</inline></reference>
                        to determine where controls should stay and move. If UIs are more
                        complex, consider learning about Containers.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </enumerated_list>
            <paragraph>And that's it! Your game should work in multiple resolutions.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="when-is-the-next-release-of-godot-out" names="when\ is\ the\ next\ release\ of\ godot\ out?">
            <title>When is the next release of Godot out?</title>
            <paragraph>When it's ready! See <reference internal="True" refuri="release_policy#doc-release-policy-when-is-next-release-out"><inline classes="std std-ref">When is the next release out?</inline></reference> for more
                information.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="which-godot-version-should-i-use-for-a-new-project" names="which\ godot\ version\ should\ i\ use\ for\ a\ new\ project?">
            <title>Which Godot version should I use for a new project?</title>
            <paragraph>We recommend using Godot 4.x for new projects, but depending on the feature set
                you need, it may be better to use 3.x instead. See
                <reference internal="True" refuri="release_policy#doc-release-policy-which-version-should-i-use"><inline classes="std std-ref">Which version should I use for a new project?</inline></reference> for more information.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="should-i-upgrade-my-project-to-use-new-godot-versions" names="should\ i\ upgrade\ my\ project\ to\ use\ new\ godot\ versions?">
            <title>Should I upgrade my project to use new Godot versions?</title>
            <paragraph>Some new versions are safer to upgrade to than others. In general, whether you
                should upgrade depends on your project's circumstances. See
                <reference internal="True" refuri="release_policy#doc-release-policy-should-i-upgrade-my-project"><inline classes="std std-ref">Should I upgrade my project to use new engine versions?</inline></reference> for more information.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="should-i-use-the-forward-mobile-or-compatibility-renderer" names="should\ i\ use\ the\ forward+,\ mobile,\ or\ compatibility\ renderer?">
            <title>Should I use the Forward+, Mobile, or Compatibility renderer?</title>
            <paragraph>You can find a detailed comparison of the renderers in <reference internal="True" refuri="../tutorials/rendering/renderers#doc-renderers"><inline classes="std std-ref">Overview of renderers</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="i-would-like-to-contribute-how-can-i-get-started" names="i\ would\ like\ to\ contribute!\ how\ can\ i\ get\ started?">
            <title>I would like to contribute! How can I get started?</title>
            <paragraph>Awesome! As an open source project, Godot thrives off of the innovation and
                the ambition of developers like you.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The best way to start contributing to Godot is by using it and reporting
                any <reference name="issues" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">issues</reference><target ids="issues" names="issues" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues"></target> that you might experience.
                A good bug report with clear reproduction steps helps your fellow contributors
                fix bugs quickly and efficiently. You can also report issues you find in the
                <reference name="online documentation" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/issues">online documentation</reference><target ids="online-documentation" names="online\ documentation" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/issues"></target>.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>If you feel ready to submit your first PR, pick any issue that resonates with you from
                one of the links above and try your hand at fixing it. You will need to learn how to
                compile the engine from sources, or how to build the documentation. You also need to
                get familiar with Git, a version control system that Godot developers use.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>We explain how to work with the engine source, how to edit the documentation, and
                what other ways to contribute are there in our <reference name="documentation for contributors" refuri="https://contributing.godotengine.org/en/latest/organization/how_to_contribute.html">documentation for contributors</reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="i-have-a-great-idea-for-godot-how-can-i-share-it" names="i\ have\ a\ great\ idea\ for\ godot.\ how\ can\ i\ share\ it?">
            <title>I have a great idea for Godot. How can I share it?</title>
            <paragraph>We are always looking for suggestions about how to improve the engine. User feedback
                is the main driving force behind our decision-making process, and limitations that
                you might face while working on your project are a great data point for us when considering
                engine enhancements.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>If you experience a usability problem or are missing a feature in the current version of
                Godot, start by discussing it with our <reference name="community" refuri="https://godotengine.org/community/">community</reference><target ids="community" names="community" refuri="https://godotengine.org/community/"></target>.
                There may be other, perhaps better, ways to achieve the desired result that community members
                could suggest. And you can learn if other users experience the same issue, and figure out
                a good solution together.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>If you come up with a well-defined idea for the engine, feel free to open a
                <reference name="proposal issue" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/issues">proposal issue</reference><target ids="proposal-issue" names="proposal\ issue" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/issues"></target>.
                Try to be specific and concrete while describing your problem and your proposed
                solution — only actionable proposals can be considered. It is not required, but
                if you want to implement it yourself, that's always appreciated!</paragraph>
            <paragraph>If you only have a general idea without specific details, you can open a
                <reference name="proposal discussion" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/discussions">proposal discussion</reference><target ids="proposal-discussion" names="proposal\ discussion" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/discussions"></target>.
                These can be anything you want, and allow for a free-form discussion in search of
                a solution. Once you find one, a proposal issue can be opened.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Please, read the <reference name="readme" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/blob/master/README.md">readme</reference><target ids="readme" names="readme" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/blob/master/README.md"></target>
                document before creating a proposal to learn more about the process.</paragraph>
            <target refid="doc-faq-non-game-applications"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="is-it-possible-to-use-godot-to-create-non-game-applications doc-faq-non-game-applications" names="is\ it\ possible\ to\ use\ godot\ to\ create\ non-game\ applications? doc_faq_non_game_applications">
            <title>Is it possible to use Godot to create non-game applications?</title>
            <paragraph>Yes! Godot features an extensive built-in UI system, and its small distribution
                size can make it a suitable alternative to frameworks like Electron or Qt.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>When creating a non-game application, make sure to enable
                <reference internal="True" refuri="../classes/class_projectsettings#class-projectsettings-property-application-run-low-processor-mode"><inline classes="std std-ref">low-processor mode</inline></reference>
                in the Project Settings to decrease CPU and GPU usage.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Check out <reference name="Material Maker" refuri="https://github.com/RodZill4/material-maker">Material Maker</reference> and
                <reference name="Pixelorama" refuri="https://github.com/Orama-Interactive/Pixelorama">Pixelorama</reference> for examples of
                open source applications made with Godot.</paragraph>
            <target refid="doc-faq-use-godot-as-library"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="is-it-possible-to-use-godot-as-a-library doc-faq-use-godot-as-library" names="is\ it\ possible\ to\ use\ godot\ as\ a\ library? doc_faq_use_godot_as_library">
            <title>Is it possible to use Godot as a library?</title>
            <paragraph>If you are looking to make a game with Godot, keep in mind Godot is designed
                to be used with its editor. We recommend you give it a try, as it
                will most likely save you time in the long term.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>For more specialized applications, it can make sense to look into using
                Godot as a library. Since Godot 4.6, there is <strong>experimental</strong> support
                for using Godot as a static or shared library in the form of LibGodot.
                This is currently supported on Windows, macOS, and Linux. Support for
                Android and iOS is planned for a future release.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>You can find sample applications that use Godot as a library in the
                <reference name="migeran/libgodot_project GitHub repository" refuri="https://github.com/migeran/libgodot_project">migeran/libgodot_project GitHub repository</reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="what-user-interface-toolkit-does-godot-use" names="what\ user\ interface\ toolkit\ does\ godot\ use?">
            <title>What user interface toolkit does Godot use?</title>
            <paragraph>Godot does not use a standard <abbreviation explanation="Graphical User Interface">GUI</abbreviation> toolkit
                like GTK, Qt or wxWidgets. Instead, Godot uses its own user interface toolkit,
                which is always rendered using hardware acceleration. There is no built-in software
                fallback, although external solutions that emulate graphics APIs on the CPU can be used.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>This toolkit is exposed in the form of Control nodes, which are used to render
                the editor (which is written in C++). These Control nodes can also be used in projects
                from any scripting language supported by Godot.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>This custom toolkit makes it possible to benefit from hardware acceleration and
                have a consistent appearance across all platforms. On top of that, it doesn't
                have to deal with the LGPL licensing caveats that come with GTK or Qt. Lastly,
                this means Godot is "eating its own dog food" since the editor itself is one of
                the most complex users of Godot's UI system.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>This custom UI toolkit can be <reference internal="True" refid="doc-faq-use-godot-as-library"><inline classes="std std-ref">embedded into other applications</inline></reference>
                (experimental). However, the preferred way to use it is to
                <reference internal="True" refid="doc-faq-non-game-applications"><inline classes="std std-ref">use Godot to create non-game applications with the editor</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
            <target refid="doc-faq-why-scons"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="why-does-godot-use-the-scons-build-system doc-faq-why-scons" names="why\ does\ godot\ use\ the\ scons\ build\ system? doc_faq_why_scons">
            <title>Why does Godot use the SCons build system?</title>
            <paragraph>Godot uses the <reference name="SCons" refuri="https://www.scons.org/">SCons</reference> build system. There are no
                plans to switch to a different build system in the near future. There are many
                reasons why we have chosen SCons over other alternatives. For example:</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="-">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Godot can be compiled for a dozen different platforms: all PC
                        platforms, all mobile platforms, many consoles, and WebAssembly.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Developers often need to compile for several of the platforms <strong>at
                            the same time</strong>, or even different targets of the same platform. They
                        can't afford reconfiguring and rebuilding the project each time.
                        SCons can do this with no sweat, without breaking the builds.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>SCons will <emphasis>never</emphasis> break a build no matter how many changes,
                        configurations, additions, removals etc.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Godot's build process is not simple. Several files are generated by
                        code (binders), others are parsed (shaders), and others need to offer
                        customization (<reference internal="True" refuri="../engine_details/architecture/custom_modules_in_cpp#doc-custom-modules-in-cpp"><inline classes="std std-ref">modules</inline></reference>). This requires
                        complex logic which is easier to write in an actual programming language (like Python)
                        rather than using a mostly macro-based language only meant for building.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Godot's build process makes heavy use of cross-compiling tools. Each
                        platform has a specific detection process, and all these must be
                        handled as specific cases with special code written for each.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>Please try to keep an open mind and get at least a little familiar with SCons if
                you are planning to build Godot yourself.</paragraph>
            <target refid="doc-faq-why-not-stl"></target>
        </section>
        <section ids="why-does-godot-not-use-stl-standard-template-library doc-faq-why-not-stl" names="why\ does\ godot\ not\ use\ stl\ (standard\ template\ library)? doc_faq_why_not_stl">
            <title>Why does Godot not use STL (Standard Template Library)?</title>
            <paragraph>Like many other libraries (Qt as an example), Godot does not make use of STL
                (with a few exceptions such as threading primitives). We believe STL is a great
                general-purpose library, but we had special requirements for Godot.</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="*">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>STL templates create very large symbols, which results in huge debug binaries. We use few
                        templates with very short names instead.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Most of our containers cater to special needs, like Vector, which uses copy on write and we
                        use to pass data around, or the RID system, which requires O(1) access time for performance.
                        Likewise, our hash map implementations are designed to integrate seamlessly with internal
                        engine types.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Our containers have memory tracking built-in, which helps better track memory usage.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>For large arrays, we use pooled memory, which can be mapped to either a preallocated buffer
                        or virtual memory.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>We use our custom String type, as the one provided by STL is too basic and lacks proper
                        internationalization support.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>Check out <reference internal="True" refuri="../engine_details/architecture/core_types#doc-core-types"><inline classes="std std-ref">Godot's container types</inline></reference> for alternatives.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="why-does-godot-not-use-exceptions" names="why\ does\ godot\ not\ use\ exceptions?">
            <title>Why does Godot not use exceptions?</title>
            <paragraph>We believe games should not crash, no matter what. If an unexpected
                situation happens, Godot will print an error (which can be traced even to
                script), but then it will try to recover as gracefully as possible and keep
                going.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>Additionally, exceptions significantly increase the binary size for the
                executable and result in increased compile times.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="does-godot-use-an-ecs-entity-component-system" names="does\ godot\ use\ an\ ecs\ (entity\ component\ system)?">
            <title>Does Godot use an ECS (Entity Component System)?</title>
            <paragraph>Godot does <strong>not</strong> use an ECS and relies on inheritance instead. While there
                is no universally better approach, we found that using an inheritance-based approach
                resulted in better usability while still being fast enough for most use cases.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>That said, nothing prevents you from making use of composition in your project
                by creating child Nodes with individual scripts. These nodes can then be added and
                removed at runtime to dynamically add and remove behaviors.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>More information about Godot's design choices can be found in
                <reference name="this article" refuri="https://godotengine.org/article/why-isnt-godot-ecs-based-game-engine">this article</reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="why-does-godot-not-force-users-to-implement-dod-data-oriented-design" names="why\ does\ godot\ not\ force\ users\ to\ implement\ dod\ (data-oriented\ design)?">
            <title>Why does Godot not force users to implement DOD (Data-Oriented Design)?</title>
            <paragraph>While Godot internally attempts to use cache coherency as much as possible,
                we believe users don't need to be forced to use DOD practices.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>DOD is mostly a cache coherency optimization that can only provide
                significant performance improvements when dealing with dozens of
                thousands of objects which are processed every frame with little
                modification. That is, if you are moving a few hundred sprites or enemies
                per frame, DOD won't result in a meaningful improvement in performance. In
                such a case, you should consider a different approach to optimization.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>The vast majority of games do not need this and Godot provides handy helpers
                to do the job for most cases when you do.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>If a game needs to process such a large amount of objects, our recommendation
                is to use C++ and GDExtensions for performance-heavy tasks and GDScript (or C#)
                for the rest of the game.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="how-can-i-support-godot-development-or-contribute" names="how\ can\ i\ support\ godot\ development\ or\ contribute?">
            <title>How can I support Godot development or contribute?</title>
            <paragraph>See <reference name="How to contribute" refuri="https://contributing.godotengine.org/en/latest/organization/how_to_contribute.html">How to contribute</reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="who-is-working-on-godot-how-can-i-contact-you" names="who\ is\ working\ on\ godot?\ how\ can\ i\ contact\ you?">
            <title>Who is working on Godot? How can I contact you?</title>
            <paragraph>See the corresponding page on the <reference name="Godot website" refuri="https://godotengine.org/contact">Godot website</reference><target ids="godot-website" names="godot\ website" refuri="https://godotengine.org/contact"></target>.</paragraph>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
