<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/community/asset_library/submitting_to_assetlib.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-submitting-to-assetlib"></target>
    <section ids="submitting-to-the-asset-library doc-submitting-to-assetlib" names="submitting\ to\ the\ asset\ library doc_submitting_to_assetlib">
        <title>Submitting to the Asset Library</title>
        <section ids="introduction" names="introduction">
            <title>Introduction</title>
            <paragraph>This tutorial aims to serve as a guide on how you can submit your own assets
                to the <reference name="Godot Asset Library" refuri="https://godotengine.org/asset-library/asset">Godot Asset Library</reference><target ids="godot-asset-library" names="godot\ asset\ library" refuri="https://godotengine.org/asset-library/asset"></target>
                and share them with the Godot community.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>As mentioned in the <reference internal="True" refuri="using_assetlib#doc-using-assetlib"><inline classes="std std-ref">Using the Asset Library</inline></reference> document, in order to be able to
                submit assets to the AssetLib, you need to have a registered account, and be
                logged in.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="submission-guidelines" names="submission\ guidelines">
            <title>Submission guidelines</title>
            <paragraph>Before submitting your asset, please ensure it follows all of the
                requirements, and also consider following the recommendations.</paragraph>
            <section ids="requirements" names="requirements">
                <title>Requirements</title>
                <paragraph>Generally speaking, most assets people submit to the asset library
                    are accepted. However, in order for your asset to be accepted, there
                    are a few requirements your asset needs to meet to be approved.</paragraph>
                <bullet_list bullet="*">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>The asset must <strong>work</strong>. If the asset doesn't run or otherwise doesn't
                            work in the specified Godot version, then it will be rejected.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>The asset must have a proper <strong>.gitignore</strong> file. It's important to
                            keep redundant data out of the repository.
                            <reference name="Here's a template." refuri="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aaronfranke/gitignore/godot/Godot.gitignore">Here's a template.</reference><target ids="here-s-a-template" names="here's\ a\ template." refuri="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aaronfranke/gitignore/godot/Godot.gitignore"></target></paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>No <strong>submodules</strong>, or any submodules must be non-essential. GitHub
                            does not include submodules in the downloaded ZIP file, so if the
                            asset needs the contents of the submodule, your asset won't work.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>The <strong>license</strong> needs to be correct. The license listed on the asset
                            library must match the license in the repository. The repo MUST
                            have a license file, called either "LICENSE" or "LICENSE.md".
                            This file must contain the license text itself and a copyright
                            statement that includes the year(s) and copyright holder.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Use proper <strong>English</strong> for the name and description of your asset.
                            This includes using correct capitalization, and using full
                            sentences in the description. You can also include other languages,
                            but there should at least be an English version.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>The icon link must be a <strong>direct link</strong>. For icons hosted on GitHub, the
                            link must start with "raw.githubusercontent.com", not "github.com".</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
            </section>
            <section ids="recommendations" names="recommendations">
                <title>Recommendations</title>
                <paragraph>These things are not required for your asset to be approved, but
                    if you follow these recommendations, you can help make the asset
                    library a better place for all users.</paragraph>
                <bullet_list bullet="*">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>When creating non-project assets, it is common practice to place your files
                            inside of an <strong>addons/asset_name/</strong> folder. Do this to avoid having your files
                            clash with other assets, or with the files of users installing your asset.
                            This folder will <strong>not</strong> be automatically generated when a user installs your asset.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Fix or suppress all script <strong>warnings</strong>. The warning system is there to
                            help identify issues with your code, but people using your asset
                            don't need to see them.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Make your code conform to the official <strong>style guides</strong>. Having a
                            consistent style helps other people read your code, and it also helps
                            if other people wish to contribute to your asset. See: the
                            <reference internal="True" refuri="../../tutorials/scripting/gdscript/gdscript_styleguide#doc-gdscript-styleguide"><inline classes="std std-ref">GDScript style guide</inline></reference> or the <reference internal="True" refuri="../../tutorials/scripting/c_sharp/c_sharp_style_guide#doc-c-sharp-styleguide"><inline classes="std std-ref">C# style guide</inline></reference>.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>If you have screenshots in your repo, place them in their own subfolder
                            and add an empty <strong>.gdignore</strong> file in the same folder (note: <strong>gd</strong>, not <strong>git</strong>).
                            This prevents Godot from importing your screenshots.
                            On Windows, open a command prompt in the project folder and run
                            <literal>type nul &gt; .gdignore</literal> to create a file whose name starts with a period.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>If your asset is a library for working with other files,
                            consider including <strong>example files</strong> in the asset.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Consider adding a <strong>.gitattributes</strong> file to your repo. This file allows
                            giving extra instructions to Git, such as specifying line endings and listing
                            files not required for your asset to function with the <literal>export-ignore</literal>
                            directive. This directive removes such files from the resulting ZIP file,
                            preventing them from being downloaded by the asset library users.
                            These are common examples of <strong>.gitattributes</strong>:</paragraph>
                        <container classes="sphinx-tabs" type="tab-element">
                            <div aria-label="Tabbed content" role="tablist">
                                <button aria-controls="panel-0-0-0" aria-selected="true" classes="sphinx-tabs-tab" ids="tab-0-0-0" name="0-0" role="tab" tabindex="0">Projects / Templates</button>
                                <button aria-controls="panel-0-0-1" aria-selected="false" classes="sphinx-tabs-tab" ids="tab-0-0-1" name="0-1" role="tab" tabindex="-1">Addons / Asset Packs</button>
                            </div>
                            <div aria-labelledby="tab-0-0-0" classes="sphinx-tabs-panel" ids="panel-0-0-0" name="0-0" role="tabpanel" tabindex="0">
                                <literal_block force="False" highlight_args="{}" language="shell" linenos="False" xml:space="preserve"># Normalize line endings for all files that Git considers text files.
* text=auto eol=lf</literal_block>
                            </div>
                            <div aria-labelledby="tab-0-0-1" classes="sphinx-tabs-panel" hidden="true" ids="panel-0-0-1" name="0-1" role="tabpanel" tabindex="0">
                                <literal_block force="False" highlight_args="{}" language="shell" linenos="False" xml:space="preserve"># Normalize line endings for all files that Git considers text files.
* text=auto eol=lf

# Only include the addons folder when downloading from the Asset Library.
/**        export-ignore
/addons    !export-ignore
/addons/** !export-ignore</literal_block>
                            </div>
                        </container>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>If you are submitting a plugin, add a <strong>copy</strong> of your license and readme
                            to the plugin folder itself. This is the folder that users are guaranteed to
                            keep with their project, so a copy ensures they always have those files handy
                            (and helps them fulfill your licensing terms).</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>While the asset library allows more than just GitHub, consider
                            hosting your asset's source code on <strong>GitHub</strong>. Other services may not
                            work reliably, and a lack of familiarity can be a barrier to contributors.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section ids="submitting" names="submitting">
            <title>Submitting</title>
            <paragraph>Once you are logged in, you will be able to head over to the "Submit Assets" page
                of the AssetLib, which will look like this:</paragraph>
            <paragraph><image alt="image0" candidates="{'*': 'community/asset_library/img/assetlib_submit.png'}" original_uri="img/assetlib_submit.png" uri="community/asset_library/img/assetlib_submit.png"></image></paragraph>
            <paragraph>While it may look like a lot (and there is more as you scroll down), each field is
                described in terms of what you should put in. We will nonetheless go over what
                is required in the submission form here as well.</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="*">
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Asset Name</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>The name of your asset. Should be a unique, descriptive title of
                                    what your asset is.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Category</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>The category that your asset belongs to, and will be shown in
                                    search results. The category is split into <strong>Addons</strong> and <strong>Projects</strong>.
                                    In-editor, assets of the Project type (Templates, Demos, Projects) only show
                                    up when viewing the AssetLib from the Project Manager, while assets of the
                                    Addon type will only be visible from inside a project.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Godot version</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>The version of the engine that the asset works with.
                                    Currently, it's not possible to have a single asset entry contain downloads for
                                    multiple engine versions, so you may need to re-submit the asset multiple times,
                                    with an entry for each Godot version it supports. This is particularly important
                                    when dealing with major versions of the engine, such as Godot 2.x and Godot 3.x.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Version</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>The version number of the asset. While you are free to choose
                                    and use any versioning scheme that you like, you may want to look into
                                    something such as <reference name="SemVer" refuri="https://semver.org">SemVer</reference><target ids="semver" names="semver" refuri="https://semver.org"></target> if you want your asset's
                                    versioning scheme to be clear and consistent. Note that there is also an
                                    internal version number, incremented every time the asset download URL is
                                    changed or updated.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Repository host</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>Assets uploaded to the AssetLib are not hosted on it
                                    directly. Instead, they point to repositories hosted on third-party Git providers,
                                    such as GitHub, GitLab or Bitbucket. This is where you choose which provider
                                    your asset uses, so the site can compute the final download link.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Repository URL</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>The URL to your asset's files/webpage. This will vary
                                    based on your choice of provider, but it should look similar to <title_reference>https://github.com/&lt;user&gt;/&lt;project&gt;</title_reference>.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Issues URL</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>The URL to your asset's issue tracker. Again, this will differ
                                    from repository host to repository host, but will likely look similar to
                                    <title_reference>https://github.com/&lt;user&gt;/&lt;project&gt;/issues</title_reference>. You may leave this field empty
                                    if you use your provider's issue tracker, and it's part of the same repository.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Download Commit</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>The commit of the asset. For example,
                                    <title_reference>b1d3172f89b86e52465a74f63a74ac84c491d3e1</title_reference>. The site computes
                                    the actual download URL from this.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Icon URL</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>The URL to your asset's icon (which will be used as a thumbnail
                                    in the AssetLib search results and on the asset's page). Should be an image
                                    in either the PNG or JPG format.</paragraph>
                                <paragraph>The <strong>icon</strong> must be square (1:1 aspect ratio). It should have a minimum
                                    resolution of 128×128 pixels.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <note>
                <paragraph>For icons hosted on GitHub, URLs must be provided in the form of <title_reference>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/&lt;user&gt;/&lt;project&gt;/&lt;branch&gt;/Icon.png</title_reference>.</paragraph>
            </note>
            <bullet_list bullet="*">
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>License</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>The license under which you are distributing the asset. The list
                                    includes a variety of free and open source software licenses, such as GPL
                                    (v2 and v3), MIT, BSD and Boost Software License. You can visit <reference name="OpenSource.org" refuri="https://opensource.org">OpenSource.org</reference><target ids="opensource-org" names="opensource.org" refuri="https://opensource.org"></target>
                                    for a detailed description of each of the listed licenses.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Description</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>Finally, you can use the Description field for a textual
                                    overview of your asset, its features and behavior, a changelog, et cetera. In the
                                    future, formatting with Markdown will be supported, but currently, your only
                                    option is plain text.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>You may also include up to three video and/or image previews, which will be shown
                at the bottom of the asset page. Use the "Enable" checkbox on each of the preview
                submission boxes to enable them.</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="*">
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Type</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>Either an image, or a video.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Image/YouTube URL</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>Either a link to the image, or to a video, hosted on YouTube.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <definition_list>
                        <definition_list_item>
                            <term><strong>Thumbnail URL</strong>:</term>
                            <definition>
                                <paragraph>A URL to an image that will be used as a thumbnail for the
                                    preview. This option will be removed eventually, and thumbnails will be automatically
                                    computed instead.</paragraph>
                            </definition>
                        </definition_list_item>
                    </definition_list>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
            <paragraph>Once you are done, press "Submit". Your asset will be entered into the review queue.
                You can check all assets currently pending a review <reference name="here" refuri="https://godotengine.org/asset-library/asset/edit?&amp;asset=-1">here</reference><target ids="here" names="here" refuri="https://godotengine.org/asset-library/asset/edit?&amp;asset=-1"></target> .
                The approval process is manual and may take up to a few days for your asset to be accepted (or rejected), so please
                be patient!</paragraph>
            <paragraph>You will be informed when your asset is reviewed. If it was rejected,
                you will be told why that may have been, and you will be able to submit it again
                with the appropriate changes.</paragraph>
            <substitution_definition names="image0"><image alt="image0" candidates="{'*': 'community/asset_library/img/assetlib_submit.png'}" original_uri="img/assetlib_submit.png" uri="community/asset_library/img/assetlib_submit.png"></image></substitution_definition>
            <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
