<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.21.2 -->
<document source="/home/runner/work/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs-cn/godot-docs/docs/community/asset_library/what_is_assetlib.rst" translation_progress="{'total': 0, 'translated': 0}" xmlns:c="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:changeset="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:citation="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:cpp="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:index="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:js="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:math="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:py="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:rst="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/" xmlns:std="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">
    <target refid="doc-what-is-assetlib"></target>
    <section ids="about-the-asset-library doc-what-is-assetlib" names="about\ the\ asset\ library doc_what_is_assetlib">
        <title>About the Asset Library</title>
        <paragraph>The Godot Asset Library, otherwise known as the AssetLib, is a repository of
            user-submitted Godot addons, scripts, tools, and other resources, collectively referred
            to as assets. They're available to all Godot users for download directly from within the
            engine, but it can also be accessed at Godot's <reference name="official website" refuri="https://godotengine.org/asset-library/asset">official website</reference><target ids="official-website" names="official\ website" refuri="https://godotengine.org/asset-library/asset"></target>.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>On the surface, the Asset Library might look and function similar to asset
            stores available for other engines, such as Unity's Asset Store, or Unreal
            Engine's Marketplace, where you can submit both freely-available assets, as well
            as paid, commercial ones. In addition, often times such assets are distributed
            under non-free, proprietary licenses, limiting what you can do with them.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>The Asset Library is different - all assets are distributed free of charge, and under
            a host of open source licenses (such as the MIT license, the GPL, and the Boost Software License).
            This makes the AssetLib more similar to the software repositories of a Linux distribution.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>This set of pages will cover how to use the AssetLib (both from inside Godot, and on the
            website), how you can submit your own assets, and what the guidelines for submission are.</paragraph>
        <paragraph>Please note that the AssetLib is relatively young - it may have various pain points, bugs,
            and usability issues. As with all Godot projects, the code repository is available on <reference name="GitHub" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-asset-library">GitHub</reference><target ids="github" names="github" refuri="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-asset-library"></target>,
            where you can submit pull requests and issues, so please do not hesitate to visit it!</paragraph>
        <section ids="types-of-assets" names="types\ of\ assets">
            <title>Types of assets</title>
            <paragraph>Be aware that there are, broadly, two different types of assets you can post.</paragraph>
            <bullet_list bullet="*">
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Assets labeled as "Templates", "Projects", or "Demos" appear under
                        the "Asset Library" tab in the Godot Project Manager. These assets are
                        standalone Godot projects that can run by themselves.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
                <list_item>
                    <paragraph>Other assets show up inside of the Godot editor under the "Asset Library"
                        main screen tab, next to "2D", "3D", and "Script". These assets are
                        meant to be downloaded and placed into an existing Godot project.</paragraph>
                </list_item>
            </bullet_list>
        </section>
        <section ids="frequently-asked-questions" names="frequently\ asked\ questions">
            <title>Frequently asked questions</title>
            <section ids="can-paid-assets-be-uploaded-to-the-asset-library" names="can\ paid\ assets\ be\ uploaded\ to\ the\ asset\ library?">
                <title>Can paid assets be uploaded to the asset library?</title>
                <paragraph>Not to the official one, though in the future, there might be other asset
                    libraries which allow it.
                    That said, you are allowed to monetize and sell Godot assets outside the
                    Asset Library.</paragraph>
                <substitution_definition names="weblate_widget"><reference refuri="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/godot-engine/?utm_source=widget"><image alt="Translation status" candidates="{'?': 'https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png'}" height="66" uri="https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/godot-engine/-/godot-docs/287x66-white.png" width="287"></image></reference></substitution_definition>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
